<Document>
# Blob

[color=#ff0000]Confirmed level 5 biohazard aboard the station. All personnel must contain the outbreak.[/color]

A blob is a fast-growing dangerous organism whose main goal is to take over the station.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CoreBlobTile" Caption="Blob"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobMouse" Caption="Carrier of the blob"/>
  </Box>

You can become a blob carrier both at the beginning of the round and in the middle if you take on the role of a ghost. Usually, the carrier of the blob is a sentient humanoid, or a mouse.

## Core

The most important blob tile is the [color=#a4885c]Core[/color]. By destroying the Core, the blob will be defeated, and all its other tiles will die, turning white.

You can always see the core health on the right side of the screen as a percentage. Watch your core and don't let it be destroyed!

There are 2 steps you can do with the Core: [color=#a4885c]transfer[/color] and [color=#a4885c]split[/color].
- When a core is transferred, the selected node and kernel are swapped. This is useful in case the kernel location is not very secure.
- When the core is split, the selected node becomes [color=#a4885c]new and independent core[/color]. Although this action requires a lot of points, in the long run, a new core can help you capture the station.

## Blob Types

Normal tiles are extremely vulnerable to burns or even mechanical damage until they're upgraded.
They can also be upgraded to strong versions, and then reflective versions, or turned into special blob tiles.
[bold]You cannot upgrade strong/reflective tiles to special tiles![/bold]

## Special tiles

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ResourceBlobTile" Caption="Resource Tile"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FactoryBlobTile" Caption="Factory Tile"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NodeBlobTile" Caption="Node Tile"/>
  </Box>

- [color=#a4885c]Resource Tiles[/color] are constantly gaining points for all the actions the blob performs. These are your second most important tiles, before the Core.
- [color=#a4885c]Factory Tiles[/color] creates Blob Pods and Blobbernauts to help fight against the station.
- [color=#a4885c]Node Tiles[/color] allow you to place other blob tiles around it within a certain radius. They will also heal Zombies and Blobbernauts when close.

## Minions

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobBlobBlobbernaut" Caption="Blobbernaut"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobBlobPod" Caption="Blob Spore"/>
  </Box>

Blob factories can produce Blob Spores and Blobbernauts, these are your bread and butter.
- Blob Spores have the ability to turn dead humanoids into zombie blobs, which will force them to fight on your side against the rest of the crew. This is your only way of defusing the Nuke, if it was activated! They will also release a cloud of smokle on death, the effect depending on your chemical.
- Blobbernauts deal a lot of damage, and are tanky, which will come in handy for attacking.

## Management

- To place a blob tile, click on an empty space. If a tile is occupied, or someone or something is standing on it, clicking on it will attack and deal damage.
- Note that [color=#a4885c]you cannot place regular blob tiles far from blob nodes. Place blob nodes to be able to grow further.[/color]
- By pressing Alt+LMB, you can upgrade normal tiles to strong tiles and strong tiles to reflective.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StrongBlobTile" Caption="Strong tiles"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReflectiveBlobTile" Caption="Reflective tiles"/>
  </Box>

## Special Abilities

In the action bar, you can use special abilities that will allow you to perform important actions, such as placing special cells, or special actions with the core and chemicals.

- [color=#a4885c]Changing chemicals[/color] allows you to change your chemical. Each has its own characteristics suitable for different situations.
- [color=#a4885c]Demote Blob[/color] gives you the option to downgrade any blob cell back to normal for free. It is useful in order to correct the wrong placement, or placing a special tile.

## Course of the round

As the blob grows, the station will pass through several stages.

- 1. [color=#a4885c]Silent stage[/color] - The blob is still undetected, and you can (probably) grow and prepare while the crew still has no idea about your existance.
- 2. [color=#a4885c]Biohazard detection[/color] - As soon as the blob grows a little, the station is automatically set to red, and complete isolation of the station is declared. The evacuation shuttle cannot be called at this point. If it was called, it will automatically be recalled.
- 3. [color=#a4885c]Delta Alert[/color] - If the blob captures a significant part of the station, Delta Alert is triggered. The main goal of the station now is to detonate the nuke, and the nuke codes will be sent to a fax machine. Defeating a blob at this point is most likely impossible.
- 4. [color=#a4885c]Critical Mass[/color] - If the blob captures a majority of the station, it reaches critical mass, causing the round to end with the blob winning.

Starting from the second stage, the captain has a priority goal in the form of protecting the nuclear authentication disk. If you lose it, the blob cannot be destroyed in Delta, which gives an near guaranteed victory to the blob! If you are the captain, do NOT charge head first into the blob!!

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="NukeDisk" Caption="Nuclear Authentication Disk"/>
  </Box>

## Methods of control

Since the blob is a biological creature, [color=#ff5500]heat and burning[/color] are the blob's main weaknesses. Burn damage is extremely effective against it, so the following weapons can help you:

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MagazineBoxPistolIncendiary" Caption="Incendiary Rounds"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponLaserCarbine" Caption="Laser Rifle"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Welder" Caption="Welder "/>
  </Box>

</Document>
