<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2023 coolmankid12345 <55817627+coolmankid12345@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Aidenkrz <aiden@djkraz.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 BombasterDS <115770678+BombasterDS@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Ghagliiarghii <68826635+Ghagliiarghii@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Killerqu00 <47712032+Killerqu00@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Piras314 <p1r4s@proton.me>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 UBlueberry <161545003+UBlueberry@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tay <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later AND MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Revolutionaries

  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"Viva la revolución!!"[/italic][/color]
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PosterContrabandRevolt" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Revolutionaries are conversion antagonists sponsored by the [color=#ff0000]Syndicate[/color] who are tasked with taking control of the station.
  Head revolutionaries are graciously given a PDA uplink, paid for by Yucatan Communications.

  ## Objectives
  You must cuff, kill, or exile all of the [textlink="Command staff" link="Command"] on station in no particular order.

  Your objective is [bold]not to destroy the station[/bold], but [italic]to take it over[/italic], so try to minimize damage as much as possible.

  [bold]The revolution will fail[/bold] if all of the [bold][color=#5e9cff]Head Revolutionaries[/color][/bold] die, and all [color=red]Revolutionaries[/color] will de-convert if this happens.

  [bold]The revolution will also fail[/bold] if all of the [bold][color=#5e9cff]Head Revolutionaries[/color][/bold] are off the station. Your objective is to capture the station, so do not wander far.

  ## Your Uplink
  [bold][color=#5e9cff]Head Revolutionaries[/color][/bold] are chosen at the start of the shift. They are given a PDA uplink similar to a Syndicate uplink.

  Telecrystals cannot be used in this PDA. Instead, a new currency, [color=#ff0000]RevCoin[/color], must be used. Be sure to lock your uplink after you're done using it.
  
  There are no restocks, so there is no point in saving RevCoin.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RevCoin"/>
  </Box>

  ## Mindshields & Eye Protection
  [color=cyan]Mindshield implanters[/color] are an obstruction to the revolution. These will:
  - Prevent the implanted person from being converted into a [color=red]Revolutionary[/color]
  - De-convert Revolutionaries, and will make them no longer loyal to your cause
  - [bold]Be visibly destroyed upon being implanted into a [color=#5e9cff]Head Revolutionary[/color][/bold], giving you away
  - NOT protect against flash disorientation

  These however, do protect against flash disorientation and conversion.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesGlassesSunglasses"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesGlassesSecurity"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHatWelding"/>
  </Box>
  
  Keep in mind that, if someone is mindshielded while a revolutionary, they are able to remember everything from their past, including who converted them.

  ## Your tools
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Flash"/>
  </Box>

  Your flash and your fast draw implanter are your bread and butter. You can remove mindshields from crew members and implant them in animals, so you can continue converting.

  You do not need a special flash. Any flash in your hands is a tool for conversion.

  People will notice when you start converting. Plan your conversions carefully, as one wrong move can alert security.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="LieutenantRevolutionaryImplanter"/>
  </Box>
  
  This tool allows you to convert an otherwise regular revolutionary to a lieutenant, allowing you to build cadres of revolutionaries ready to act on a moments notice.
  
  This is your organizing tool. These lieutenants, while unable to convert anyone, can see the revolutionary status of all crew on-board. 
  
  They also have intrinsic radio access to the Syndicate channel, allowing them to co-ordinate with you from anywhere on the station.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RevsFastDrawImplanter"/>
  </Box>

  This implanter removes implants, quickly. A regular implanter takes 60 seconds to remove a single implant, while this only takes 30 seconds.
  Useful for when you want to get command or security on your side.

  Be sure to [bold]toggle your implanter[/bold] to remove a mindshield, as you will deal great damage if you attempt to remove the wrong one!

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeySyndie"/>
  </Box>

  An encryption key that allows you to speak to other operatives and head revolutionaries on the station. Useful for long way communication, not-so-useful if you are caught.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingEyesGlassesSunglasses"/>
  </Box>

  Style. Prevents you from being flashed. Useful if you are being chased by security or over-zealous crew members.

  ## Extra Tools

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GrenadeFlashBangRevolutionary"/>
  </Box>

  This flash can convert anyone in its flash radius, useful for causing mayhem. You must take a screwdriver to a flash and mess with it. Only head revolutionaries have access to this incredible power, so keep it well hidden.
  Only head revolutionaries can throw the revolutionary flashbang and have it convert people.
</Document>
