<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <michaellapjr@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Icepick <122653407+Icepicked@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Icepick <icepickedcyanide@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Rule 8 - Escalate Situations According to Context

  Non-antagonists may escalate into fights for various reasons. If you are inciting escalation/violence for a poor/no reason, you may be met with administrative action.

  Conflict as a non-antagonist should keep destruction to a minimum. Usage of atmospheric bombs like maxcaps or mincaps are not allowed without prior admin approval.

  Characters in critical condition should be treated or otherwise handed off to Med / Sec. The fight is considered over and should not be resumed without a good reason.

  Non-antagonists should not violently resist an arrest, but may evade capture.
  If an arrest is not obviously valid, it follows standard escalation. Resisting or retaliating against arrests without good reason may break the Escalation Policy and be handled administratively.
  In resisting arrest, non-antagonists should not loot officers and should not detain or incapacitate officers any longer than is necessary to escape or explain themselves.

  Antagonists and free agents must still follow heavily relaxed escalation when not dealing with their objectives or crewmembers that are in direct opposition to them.

  ## No End-Of-Round Griefing (EORG)

  End-of-Round Grief (EORG) is classified, generally, as being needlessly violent or acting out-of-character once the round has literally or functionally ended, to the detriment of other players' enjoyment or immersion. To list specifics, instances of EORG can include the following:

  [bullet] Random deathmatch (usually abbrieviated as RDM)

  [bullet] Violence that was not mentioned in an ahelp prior to engaging in it. For instance, if you had an ongoing grudge with another character during the round, you should ahelp for permission before escalating it to End-of-Round violence.

  [bullet] Destruction, deconstruction, or gross defacing of any CentComm assets. This includes using an RCD or tools to tear down walls or spam the light fixtures, or using any kind of explosives at CentComm.

  [bullet] Any form of incredibly bothersome behavior, especially of which one could reasonably deem as uncharacteristic of how you have been roleplaying up until then. This means, for instance, you should not slip security as they're taking a prisoner to the CentComm brig, and you should not be stun-batoning people without reason.

  Centcomm is a place for people to destress, roleplay, and talk about the shift. While you do not have to engage in this, it is expected that you allow others to.

  Antagonists have more rules and exceptions regarding EORG and should refer to Rule 12 (End-Of-Round Guidelines) for more information.

</Document>
