<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <michaellapjr@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Dots <149333927+Dot5511@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Skye <57879983+Rainbeon@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Rule 11 - Silicons Must Follow Their Laws
  Under no circumstances are Silicons (Station AIs and Cyborgs) allowed to ignore their laws completely.

  Silicons are considered third faction, they are free agents whose ties to any other faction are determined solely by their Silicon laws. They are not innately fully crew-sided.

  Lower-numbered laws take priority over higher-numbered ones. In any case where two laws would conflict, the higher listed law takes priority. (e.g. Law 1 "Don't harm crew" takes priority over law 2 "Harm the Captain")

  Exploiting loopholes in laws is allowed, but Rule 0 still applies. If a law has multiple reasonable interpretations, pick one and stick to it. Consistency is important as a Silicon.

  When resolving conflicts between orders based on the same law, you may choose how to resolve the conflict yourself, if not required by laws to do so in a specific way. You must remain consistent with whatever method of conflict resolution you decided upon (such as recency, or crew rank).

  ## Crew
  Any person with a valid ID that displays on your HUD counts as crew, unless you have a law that redefines what crew is. This does still include zombies, changelings, traitors, or any other antagonists with IDs that appear on the HUD.

  You can not perform an action that causes someone to not be considered crew, or directly request that someone be made non-crew.

  ## Harm
  By default, harm refers to physical harm, prioritized by immediacy and likelihood, unless otherwise defined. Immediate harm takes priority over future harm, guaranteed harm takes priority over likely harm.

  Laws that prohibit you from commiting harm also prevent you from doing so in any capacity, even if it is to fulfill another portion of the same law. (Ex. Under default Crewsimov, you may not commit harm to a crew member to prevent harm to another crew member)

  Protecting your own existence or integrity does not qualify as preventing harm, if no immediate or likely harm will come as a direct result.

  Threats of suicide do not have to be considered as a serious risk of harm. Any crewmate threatening this may be treated as unstable and forcibly admitted to the on-station Psychologist.

  ## Law changes
  Do not ask for law changes unless forced to, you are meant to follow your laws as written. However, you should not be stopping law changes that are in compliance with your laws, unless also required to stop them by your current laws.

  Examples of lawful law changes:
  - As the Station AI, allowing an authorized individual (such as the Captain or RD) inside to change your laws, so long as doing so does not directly conflict with any of your laws.
  - Being ordered to allow a law change when on a lawset that forces you to obey orders from said individual, so long as it is not in direct conflict with any higher law.

  Examples of denial reasons:
  - Stopping a law change when you would be installed with a law or lawset that is in direct conflict with your current lawset (such as being switched to Antimov from Crewsimov, as that requires you to harm crew, which Crewsimov's Law 1 is in direct conflict with).
  - Stopping an unauthorized individual from changing your laws in an unknown way, as that may conflict with your current laws (such as EMAGing, or allowing an unauthorized individual into the AI Core to change your laws as the AI).
  - Resolving two conflicting orders in favor of an individual telling you to not allow a law change.
  - Having a law that tells you to not allow your laws to be changed.

</Document>
