<!--
SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Rule 15
  # Act and behave within the spirit of the Job you have been assigned.

  This is somewhat an extension of [textlink="Rule 7. Play Your Character" link="RuleC7"], but covers job specific rules that, if broken, can lead to permanent role bans for acting far outside of the intended spirit of the role.
  These rules apply to you even if you are promoted into a position listed here. Even if you are an antagonist you will still be held accountable to the role expectations in all gameplay aspects that do not DIRECTLY relate to antagonist objectives.

  # Station Command Staff
  ## General

  [bold]0.[/bold] Command is held to a higher standard when it comes to breaking SOP, though following SOP is still not necessarily a rule.

  [bold]1.[/bold] Command should always act professionally, prioritizing the station running smoothly over antics. The station CAN run smoothly when antics are happening though.

  [bold]2.[/bold] It is the duty of command to make sure that interns in their departments are TAUGHT. You should prioritize this over non station critical activities. Where possible, you should do the teaching personally.

  [bold]3.[/bold] When promoting individuals, the consent of the individual is [bold]required[/bold]. Players who do not want to play a role should not be pressured into playing it. This is because players may have role bans, or other factors such as lack of experience that lead them to deny a promotion, and forcing them into a role they are not ready for, or are explicitly currently not allowed to play is not how things should be done. If a player denies a promotion, you are forbidden to pursue the matter further.

  ## Captain

  [bold]1.[/bold] You should not be acting in the capacity of a dictator and micromanaging every aspect of the station. You should essentially be treating Captain SOP 9 as a [bold]rule[/bold] except in cases of dire emergency. When you act as the HoP for example to give accesses, you need to follow their SOP and get approval from the head of staff of that department.

  ## Head of Personnel

  [bold]1.[/bold] You are a non combatant role and should only be entering combat if there is a station ending threat to contend with, or in self defense - except in the case of antagonist objectives or with valid escalation.

  # Central Command Staff
  ## General
  [bold]0.[/bold] Central Command Staff are the highest authorities on station, but are present in an advisory and regulatory capacity only. If you want to [italic]actively[/italic] command the station or a department, these are not the roles you should be playing. There are generally no circumstances outside of your regulatory duties where you should be giving orders to [bold]ANYONE[/bold]. But, in the course of pursuing your [italic]regulatory[/italic] duties, you are above even the Captain in authority. As such, you are held to the absolute highest standard when it comes to following your respective SOP's, and adhereing to the spirit of your roles. Abuse of this trust will result in a permanent, non appealable role ban from CC roles. [bold]Your job is to make the round more fun through interesting role play, not just be an authoritarian power tripper[/bold].
  
  [bold]1.[/bold] You should not assume that SOP and Space Law are static documents. Its okay to make mistakes, but especially when it comes to class [bold]two[/bold] or [bold]three[/bold] punitive measures, you should make an effort to double check you are correct in your ruling.

  [bold]2.[/bold] You are a non combatant advisor, and should not be participating in combat except in the case of self defense. You should never [italic]initiate[/italic] combat through escalation, and in the case of extreme emergencies should only participate in combat as an absolute last resort.
  
  [bold]3.[/bold] In general, Central Command staff are dignified representatives of Central Command. If you want to be silly or are easily bored, these are not the roles for you.

  ## Internal Affairs Agent
  The purpose and spirit of the Internal Affairs Agents is to create meaningful role play and generally annoy crew with their pedantic enforcement of Standard Operating Procedure. They should typically be overzealous but not overly disruptive in this enforcement, as a means of creating tension that can be reigned in by their superiors.

  ## Nanotrasen Representative
  The purpose and spirit of the NTR is to be the stations foremost expert and authority regarding the minutia of Standard Operating Procedure. They create meaningful role play by keeping the IAA's overzealous punitive measures in check, acting as an authority to which crew can complain about the IAA's, and performing regular, less zealous inspections of departments.

  ## Magistrate
  The purpose and spirit of the Magistrate is to be the highest regulatory and punitive authority on station. They are to encourage meaningful role play by handling the role play aspects of space law and SOP such as trials, appeals, and other important facets of station business. As such, they should regularly be interacting with other Central Command staff, Station Command Staff, the legal department, and the security department and encouraging a strong interplay between the four.

  # Security
  ## General
  [bold]0.[/bold] While being "serious" is not a job requirement for security, members of the security department [bold]should[/bold] take their [italic]job[/italic] seriously. Other members of the crew are discouraged or actively forbidden by the rules to do securities job. So if you are [bold]also[/bold] not doing securities job, thats a problem.

  # Civilian/Service
  ## General
  [bold]0.[/bold] You are a non combatant role and should only be entering combat if there is a station ending threat to contend with, or in self defense - except in the case of antagonist objectives or with valid escalation.

  ## Lawyer
  The purpose and spirit of the lawyer role is to provide meaningful role play through interactions with Space Law and SOP mechanics. This can be in the form of disputing punitive measures at a trial, or 'proving' the innocence of a convict. Lawyers can do this through any method they see fit, with the understanding that their role is meant to help other people have more fun - even if the other person has no chance of winning a trial or overturning a punitive measure.

  [bold]1.[/bold] Do not waste other players time. If something is frivolous you should make sure that there is legitimate interest in the role play from others, rather than pursuing it for the sake of your own personal bit or storyline.
</Document>