<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <michaellapjr@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Icepick <122653407+Icepicked@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Icepick <icepickedcyanide@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Mish <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Rule 6 - No Metagaming

  This rule includes all methods of gaining information outside of in-character means, such as conversations through Discord calls, discussing current round information through the Discord server, so on and so forth

  This rule limits the knowledge of antagonists and their possible objectives as well as their mechanics in accordance to the [textlink="Metashield" link="Metashield"].

  This rule extends to metacommunications, or multiple players communicating outside of the game (e.g. on a voice call) while also playing the game.
  Regardless of intent, this is forbidden as it inherently provides an advantage over other players.
  If you are teaching a new player, it is highly recommended to use LOOC channels or message an admin using F1 to notify them.

  This also includes antag-rolling, or the practice of joining a server exclusively to play an antagonist (including ghost roles). This is heavily frowned upon and will result in a ban when caught, don't do it.

  No information while in critical condition, unconscious, or dead can be used in-character under any circumstances unless it is learned about while alive. This is enforced strictly, especially in cases where it is used to “metagrudge”, or to hold a grudge against somebody who killed you in previous rounds or lives.

  When you are revived either by cloning, MMI, defibrillation, or some other method, you are not aware of the circumstances of your death unless told by another person, including who killed you.

  When freed from a brainwashing or mind control, you are allowed but not required to remember all events, names, people, and actions taken during the time you were under.

  Powergaming is best described as the usage of meta mechanics and/or reasoning in order to gain an IC advantage over other players (e.g. arming up Security at the start of the round because you know antagonists exist). This is also frowned upon.

  Follow the [textlink="Metashield" link="Metashield"]
</Document>
