<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <michaellapjr@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Icepick <122653407+Icepicked@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Icepick <icepickedcyanide@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Rule 1 - Don't be an Asshole

  These rules are not perfect. The rules attempt to clearly communicate what the admin team intends to be allowed and prohibited, but there are likely loopholes or other flaws that can be "lawyered". Don't attempt to manipulate the interpretation of the rules to suit your personal goals or to degrade the experience of other players.

  Everybody here's playing a game to have fun. Being an asshole in character is allowed, with the expectation that they're played with nuance and respect for others. But extension of that outside of gameplay is strictly forbidden.

  This includes bigotry, any of which will get a quick ban. [bold]This is zero-tolerance.[/bold]

  This also includes self-antag or griefing or any other form of intentionally ruining others fun for the sake of your own experience.

  Consistently toeing the line on these rules will be treated as rule violations and will get you banned.
  
  Characters that only exist to manufacture or spark drama, dominate the scene, or make everything about them are not allowed.

  Insults should not be repeatedly and lazily hurled at players. If someone asks you to stop out of character, then stop. Continuing to do so will violate this rule.
  
  There is a person behind each character in round. Keep insults contextual, un-targeted, and out of OOC.
  
  If you play an incendiary character, then expect incendiary responses.

  Sometimes players must step away from the game due to IRL circumstances or connection issues, and out of respect for these issues players that are Disconnected, in Cryosleep, or otherwise "SSD" should not be antagonized or exploited while they are unable to act to defend themselves. Players in these circumstances should not be stolen from, used to open doors, used as meatshields, or directly attacked unless you have an antagonist objective specifically targeting that player or an item that can ONLY be found on their person, such as the Nuclear Authentication Disk. These players may be moved freely to Medical, Security, or EVAC for safekeeping and healing. Players who are Puple-Text Catatonic or have been SSD for over 30 minutes  should be taken to Cryosleep to free up their role slot. If a player that is disconnected is your target, you may also ahelp to ask for a new target.
  
  [bold]Players can retaliate following escalation rules.[/bold]

</Document>
