<!--
SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Rule 14
  # Be mindful of the immersion of others.

  This is a role playing game, and as such players often have varying levels of immersion within the setting and as their characters. Players are expected to respect this by not acting in ways that can inadvertantly upset other players immersion, even if other players might be aiming for a higher level of immersion than themselves.

  LOOC is a tool for communicating information that CANNOT otherwise be communicated in game.

  Use of LOOC for communicating current round information should follow the premise of If it CAN be said in character it SHOULD be said in character. If it SHOULD NOT be said in character, it SHOULD NOT be said in LOOC.  In general, current round information should almost NEVER be talked about in LOOC. A clown shooting themselves with a gun they stole from a secoff should be reacted to in chracter, not "LOL" in LOOC chats. This extends to antags, such as HOS saying: "I know they're a ling but I cant prove it so I guess we let them go"

  Use of LOOC for communicating out of character information that is not game relevant should be avoided. This includes "OMG, hi xX_TimberWolf1984_Xx, how has your day been?" - out of character conversations with friends do not belong in game chats as a rule of thumb. If you would like to speak with your friends, speak to them in discord, or speak to them in character.

  Use of LOOC for communicating out of character information that is game relevant, such as "I am going SSD for a bit" or "The default keybind is E for that action" are good examples of appropriate use.

  Misuse of LOOC chats may result in a reduction in your daily LOOC budget, or outright removal of your ability to use the LOOC chat channel.

  Antagonists should write pinktext in character. It is meant to be how your character would describe their accomplishments during the shift.

  Use of pinktext to mald out of character at other players or mechanics that got in your way is not allowed. You can talk about how the HOS foiled your plans, you should not be saying "I lagged out so the shitsec stuncuffed me before I could escape." or "I didn't lmao." If you do this you are liable to be warned or banned for No intent to roleplay or OOC Toxicity.

</Document>
