<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Skye <57879983+Rainbeon@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 kbarkevich <24629810+kbarkevich@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Terkala <appleorange64@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later OR MIT
-->

<Document>
# Blood Cult

[color=#ff3333][italic]The oldest and strongest emotion of mankind is fear, and the oldest and strongest kind of fear is fear of the unknown.[/italic][/color]

The blood cult is a loosely-organized group of acolytes dedicated to an interdimensional being: [color=#ff3333]Nar'Sie, the Geometer of Blood[/color]. For as long as its existence has been documented, its main goal has been to identify a location suitable for the barriers between spatio-temporal dimensions -- the "veil" -- to be broken down. It is theorized that, if they were to accomplish this, an [color=#ff3333]unspeakable horror of ancient power[/color] that wishes to bring ruin to the universe and shape it into their image would be brought forth into our reality.

Obviously, this cannot be allowed to occur.

Unfortunately for the station, it looks like Nanotrasen accidentally positioned it near an undetectable weak point in time and space. Whoops. Who would've known?
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TearVeilRune" Caption="The sigil of Nar'Sie."/>
  </Box>

As a blood cultist, the only being you love more than your fellow acolytes is [color=#ff3333]Nar'Sie Herself[/color]. Be kind to one another, teach each other the tricks and tools of the trade, and remember that only through complete co-operation can you achieve your [color=#dd55aa]goal[/color].

You can become a blood cultist both at the beginning of the round and by being converted by existing acolytes. Cultists may also, instead, choose to trap your soul in a stone to do their bidding.

## Abilities

[color=#ff3333]Your patron[/color] has seen fit to empower [color=#ff3333]Her[/color] blood cultists with several basic abilities to help you on your quest.

<Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ActionCultistCommune" Caption="Commune"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ActionCultistStudyVeil" Caption="Study Veil"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ActionCultistSpellsSelect" Caption="Prepare Spell"/>
  </Box>

The [bold]Commune[/bold] ability allows a cultist to speak to their fellow acolytes over any distance. However, an incantation will be audibly whispered. Beware of alerting the crew to your cult's presence too early through unwise use of this ability. If the veil has been torn, this incantation is audible to those around you.

The [bold]Study Veil[/bold] ability allows a cultist to hear [color=#ff3333]the Geometer[/color]'s voice. Recieve your instructions through the use of this ability.

The [bold]Prepare Spell[/bold] ability allows [color=#ff3333]your patron[/color] to reach forth and carve [bold]Blood Spell[/bold] sigils onto your flesh. Only one blood spell may be prepared at a time, unless the user is standing atop an [color=#ff6666]empowering rune[/color].

## Runes

Your bread-and-butter as a cultist are your [color=#ff6666]Runes.[/color] These sigils, painted in your own wrist's blood, allow acolytes to draw upon the power of [color=#ff3333]Nar'Sie[/color] at a concentrated physical location.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OfferingRune" Caption="the"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmpoweringRune" Caption="runes"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReviveRune" Caption="of"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BarrierRune" Caption="your cult"/>
  </Box>

[color=#ff6666]Runes[/color] can be drawn at your feet by activating a cult dagger in your hand, selecting a rune from the radial menu that appears, and then using the dagger on yourself. Beware -- this will hurt.

The most important runes you have available are the [color=#ff6666]offering rune[/color] and the [color=#ff6666]empowering rune[/color]. With these runes placed in a safe location, cultists may begin enacting [color=#dd55aa]the will of their mistress[/color].

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OfferingRune" Caption="offering rune"/>
  </Box>

The [bold][color=#ff6666]offering rune[/color][/bold] allows cultists to convert the weak-minded to their cause. Once the [color=#ff3333]Geometer[/color] has risen, her power can destroy mental protections on those offered to her.
- [color=#EEEE33]Converting[/color] a living, weak-minded individual to your cause -- an individual who is not mindshielded, not a Chaplain.
- [color=#99CC99]Breaking[/color] the mindshield of their mental protections can only be done if the [color=#ff3333]Geometer[/color] has risen.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmpoweringRune" Caption="empowering rune"/>
  </Box>

The [bold][color=#ff6666]empowering rune[/color][/bold] allows a cultist standing on it to prepare more than one blood spell at a time. In addition, the preparation of these spells will result in far less physical trauma to the envoker, and will be performed significantly faster.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ReviveRune" Caption="revive rune"/>
  </Box>

The [bold][color=#ff6666]revive rune[/color][/bold] may be used by cultists to ask [color=#ff3333]Nar'Sie[/color] to restore the soul of a lost acolyte. A dead cultist may be dragged on top of this rune, and the rune subsequently activated, to make this request. However, [color=#ff3333]She[/color] may demand further sacrifices be made before deigning [color=#ff3333]herself[/color] to fetch this lost soul. 
- [color=#ff6666]revive rune[/color] can also revive non worshippers of [color=#ff3333]Nar'Sie[/color]. She demands a tithe of blood for this service, and will not heal them fully until their souls have been offered to her.


  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="BarrierRune" Caption="barrier rune"/>
  </Box>

The [bold][color=#ff6666]barrier rune[/color][/bold] allows the [color=#ff3333]Geometer[/color] to physically defend [color=#ff3333]Her[/color] followers through the use of magical barriers. When activated, an impenetrable forcefield will temporarily manifest above it, and any adjacent [color=#ff3333]barrier runes[/color] will be activated as well. There is no limit to the length of this chain, save for the fortitude of the invoker -- their blood will be drained for the ritual at a rate determined by the number of barriers produced.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SummoningRune" Caption="summoning rune"/>
  </Box>

The [bold][color=#ff6666]summoning rune[/color][/bold] allows the [color=#ff3333]Geometer[/color] to physically manifest [color=#ff3333]Her[/color] structures and servants from her realm into our own. When activated, a summoning rune will bring a [color=#ff3333]Juggernaut Shell[/color] or a [color=#ff3333]Pylon[/color] into reality, using runed steel or glass.


## Blood Spells

Blood spells are incantations that must be physically carved into the invoker's skin by a [color=#ff3333]higher entity[/color] prior to their use. Fortunately for you, as the veil is thin in this sector of space, [color=#ff3333]your Patron[/color] is capable of reaching forth and etching the appropriate sigils onto your person without your hands needing to be free or unrestrained. Without the aid of an [color=#ff6666]empowering rune[/color], however, the carving will have to be a crude one, and there may only be enough room on your body for one sigil at a time.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ActionCultistSummonDagger" Caption="Summon Dagger"/>
  </Box>

The summon dagger spell allows a cultist to instantly grant themselves a weapon and a rune-carving tool. Useful for new devotees and those who have lost their old daggers.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ActionCultistSanguineDream" Caption="Sanguine Dream"/>
  </Box>

The Sanguine Dream spell plunges a victim into a nightmare-filled sleep where they dream of blood-soaked knives. This also drains energy from cybernetic entities. This does not work on those with a mindshield.

This spell may permit you to silently and more efficiently kidnap those your cult requires. It will not work on those whos minds are shielded. It is recommended that all cultists keep a Sanguine Dream spell prepared when roaming beyond their selected base of operations, [bold]just in case.[/bold]

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ActionCultistTwistedConstruction" Caption="Twisted Construction"/>
  </Box>

The twisted construction spell allows cultists to convert stacks of steel or glass or plasteel into [color=#bbbbbb]runed steel[/color] or [color=#bbbbbb]runed glass[/color] or [color=#bbbbbb]runed plasteel[/color].

## Structures

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultPylon" Caption="Pylon"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultJuggernautShell" Caption="Juggernaut Shell"/>
  </Box>

Structures are worldly objects that possess a mere drop of [color=#ff3333]Her[/color] being. Constructable using [color=#bbbbbb]runed steel[/color] via a summining rune. Place the materials upon the rune to summon them. These objects are a great boon to a developed cult.

Pylons will gradually heal those devoted to [color=#ff3333]Nar'Sie[/color], including inhabited constructs. By merely existing near them, living devotees will continuously receive [color=#ff3333]Her[/color] blessing, knitting bone and sinew and undoing any half-baked attempts at deconversion.

Juggernaut shells are inert statues of [color=#bbbbbb]runed steel[/color]. They are completely useless... until an inhabited soul stone or dead body is inserted, at least.

## Constructs

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobBloodCultShade" Caption="Shade"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobBloodCultJuggernaut" Caption="Juggernaut"/>
  </Box>

Constructs are non-verbal, barely-sentient minions of the blood cult. Made from the twisted souls sacrificed to the [color=#ff3333]Geometer[/color], these entities count towards completing rituals with [color=#ff6666]runes[/color], and may be used in place of living cultists in a pinch.

Shades are mostly-physical spirits produced by activating an inhabited soul stone in one's hand. Loyal to the one who freed them, Shades will stop at nothing to see their master's will enacted. What they lack in physical strength they make up for in speed and endurance. A shade will return to their soulstone when banished.

Juggernauts are hulking beasts made from juggernaut shells, awakened through the insertion of an inhabited soul stone or dead body. Slow and meticulous, these monstrosities are completely immune to weak attacks, and are capable of breaking down even the strongest of walls. An invaluable asset to a cult whose presence aboard the station is already known.
- Juggernauts may be rejuvinated by letting them absorb blood from puddles beneath them and inactive shells may be repaired by inserting a soulstone or body and also letting them absorb blood from puddles beneath them.

## Items

  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CultDaggerCurved" Caption="Cult Dagger"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingOuterArmorCult" Caption="Acolyte Armor"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadHelmetCult" Caption="Cult Helmet"/>
	<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingShoesBootsForsaken" Caption="Forsaken Boots"/>
  </Box>

A cult is incomplete without their tools. Most important of which is your Cult Dagger. You can summon daggers via your spell selection ability.
The cult dagger is a decent melee weapon that can be used to attack enemies and carve runes. It is incapable of harming fellow cult members, so you can swing freely without risk of harming your allies.

The following items are all constructed via a summoning rune. Place the materials upon the rune to summon them.

Acolyte Armor is a set of armor that will protect you from most attacks. It is made from runed plasteel and outerwear clothing to hold the armor plates. Your Twisted Construction spell allows you to convert plasteel into runed plasteel.
Cult Helmet is much as you would expect, and is constructed at the same time as the Acolyte Armor.
Forsaken Boots are very important for a cultist to have. They allow your boots to grip the ground with unnatural force, and prevent you from slipping. They can be made from 5 plastic and 5 cloth, or simply from 5 durathread.

## The Dual Rituals of Nar'Sie

### Tearing the Veil

When the veil has been sufficiently weakened, and your cult has grown sufficiently expanded, it will be time to summon [color=#ff3333]your master.[/color]

A new rune may be drawn at any of the three designated locations [color=#ff3333]She[/color] will tell you about. This rune will take a long time to prepare.

Once the veil is torn, the cult will be known to the crew and will no longer be able to hide in any way.

### Summoning Nar'Sie

Once the veil is torn, the geometer will begin her journey to this plane of existence. She will find the weakest point in the fabric of space-time and tear it apart.

This will manifest in our reality as a bloody tear. Find this tear and perform the final ritual breaking through the walls of reality.

You will need several cultists to stand on the offering runes and perform the final ritual. If the runes have been wiped away, you can redraw them.

This final ritual will incur a dark cost on the cultists performing it, but will end with her glorious return.

## Course of the Round

As the cult expands, the situation aboard the station will pass through several stages.

- 1. [color=#a4885c]Silent[/color] - The cult begins to expand, few have joined the cult. The veil is still strong.
- 2. [color=#a4885c]Eyes[/color] - Her eyes are upon you. She is watching. She is waiting. Her power will leak through the veil and glow faintly from the eyes of the cultists.
- 3. [color=#a4885c]Rise[/color] - She has fully awoken. Her power has grown and she can bring her full power to break feeble mental protections of those offered to her.
- 4. [color=#a4885c]Veil[/color] - The veil has been weakened. The cult can begin to perform the final ritual once her rift is visible.
- 5. [italic][color=#ff3333]She is here.[/color][/italic] - [italic][color=#ff3333]despair[/color][italic]

## Combatting the Cult

Deconverting a blood cultist can happen in four ways
1. Is through the forced imbibement of [color=#4466ff]holy water[/color] (at least 40u).
2. Is by implanting a [color=#4466ff]mindshield[/color] into the cultist.
3. Is by using a [color=#4466ff]censer[/color] on the cultist.
4. Is by throwing a container of holy water onto the blood spilled by a cult. This will form a holy fog that will burn and purify cultists.
5. By spraying a cultist with holy water from a spray bottle or extinguisher. Or splashing a container of holy water on them. It will burn and eventually purify them.

Your Chaplain, a holy being, is largely immune to the more [italic]persuasive[/italic] aspects of the blood cult's methods, and is the only crewmember who may be trusted absolutely once the cult's presence is known. Chaplains are also resistant to blood magic and cult-manufactured weaponry, rendering the offensive abilities of most cultists useless against them -- unless the cultists resort to more traditional methods of attack.

Protect the Chaplain, for their holy water is the only thing that stands between you and [bold][color=#ff3333]consumption[/color][/bold].

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RandomHumanoidVisitorChaplain" Caption="Your sole line of defense. God help you."/>
  </Box>

</Document>
