<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Head of Personnel SOP

[bold]1.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may [bold]not[/bold] transfer any personnel to another Department without authorization from the relevant [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color]. If no [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color] is available, the Head of Personnel may make a judgment call. This does not apply to Security, which always requires authorization from the [color=#cb0000]Head of Security[/color]. If there is no Head of Security active, no transfers are allowed to Security without authorization from the [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may [bold]not[/bold] give any personnel increased access without authorization from the relevant [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color]. This includes Head of Personnel. In addition, the Head of Personnel may only give [color=#1b67a5]Captain-Level[/color] access to someone if they are the [color=#1b67a5]Acting Captain[/color]. This access is to be removed when a proper [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color] arrives at the station;

[bold]3.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may [bold]not[/bold] increase any Job Openings unless the relevant [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color] approves;

[bold]4.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may [bold]not[/bold] fire any personnel without authorization from the relevant [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color], unless other conditions apply (see Space Law and General Standard Operating Procedure);

[bold]5.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may [bold]not[/bold] promote anyone to any [color=#009100]Central Command[/color] role. The use of [color=#009100]Central Command ID[/color] icons is also prohibited without explicit approval;

[bold]6.[/bold] The Head of Personnel is free to utilize paperwork at their discretion. However, during major station emergencies, expediency should take precedence over bureaucracy;

[bold]7.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may [bold]not[/bold] leave their office unmanned if there are personnel waiting in line. Failure to respond to personnel with a legitimate request within ten (10) minutes, either via radio or in person is to be considered a breach of Standard Operating Procedure;

[bold]8.[/bold] The Head of Personnel is [bold]not[/bold] permitted to perform [color=#cb0000]Security[/color] duty. The Head of Personnel is permitted to carry a Disabler for self-defense only.

## Head of Personnel OOC Rules
[textlink="Act and behave within the spirit of the Job you have been assigned" link="RuleC15"]
</Document>
