<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Goomson <GoomsonCode@proton.me>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Ingredient Reactions
  Here are the ingredient creation reactions that, by and large, any chef should be able to use in their kitchen.

  Though kitchens start out well-stocked with a variety of reagent ingredients already, it may not be clear how those reagents turn into some of the ingredients that you can cook with.

  #Doughs
  
  Quite almost literally the bread of the chef's kitchen, dough comes in quite a few varieties - all of them made in a reaction!

  ##Standard Doughs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodDough" Caption="Regular Dough"/>
  </Box>
  You can make regular dough by combining the following reagents:

  -15u Flour
  -10u Water

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodDoughTortilla" Caption="Tortilla Dough"/>
  </Box>
  You can make tortilla dough by combining the following reagents:

  -15u Cornmeal
  -10u Water

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodDoughCotton" Caption="Cotton Dough"/>
  </Box>
  For the station's fiber-eating personnel, you can make cotton dough by combining the following reagents:

  -10u Fiber
  -5u Flour
  -10u Water

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodDoughCornmeal" Caption="Cornmeal Dough"/>
  </Box>
  You can make cornmeal dough by combining the following reagents:

  -15u Cornmeal
  -10u Milk
  -6u Raw Egg

  You can generally cut and roll these doughs.

  ##Specialty Doughs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodDoughPie" Caption="Pie Dough"/>
  </Box>
  You can make pie dough, the consumable part of a pie, by combining with the following reagents:

  -15u Flour
  -12u Raw Egg
  -5u Table Salt

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodCakeBatter" Caption="Cake Batter"/>
  </Box>
  You can make cake batter by combining one of the following sets of reagents:

  -15u Flour
  -12u Raw Egg
  -5u Sugar
  -5u Milk
  
  OR:
  
  -15u Flour
  -15u Soy Milk
  -5u Sugar

  While the end result may be the same regardless of the recipe you use, those with milk and egg allergies will thank you for using the soy recipe.

  #Catalyzed Reactions

  Though every ingredient does consume reagents to be made, not every reaction will consume all of the reagents that go into making them.

  Catalysts are the names for those reagents which will not be used up when making an ingredient. They will react so long as a minimum amount of them is present.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodButter" Caption="Butter"/>
  </Box>
  You can make a stick of butter by combining the following reagents:

  -30u Milk
  -5u Table Salt as a catalyst

  ##Enzyme Reactions
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodCheese" Caption="Cheese"/>
  </Box>
  You can make a wheel of cheese by combining the following reagents:

  -40u Milk
  -5u Universal Enzyme as a catalyst

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodChevre" Caption="Chèvre"/>
  </Box>
  You can make a log of chèvre, goats' milk cheese, by combining the following reagents:

  -10u Goats Milk
  -5u Universal Enzyme as a catalyst

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodTofu" Caption="Tofu"/>
  </Box>
  You can make a block of tofu by combining the following reagents:

  -30u Soy Milk
  -5u Universal Enzyme as a catalyst

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMysteryMeat" Caption="Mystery meat...?"/>
  </Box>
  You can reconstitute a slab of mystery meat by combining the following reagents:

  -10u Uncooked Animal Proteins
  -5u Universal Enzyme as a catalyst

  #Miscellaneous Reactions

  While a vast majority of the reactions a chef may need to use have been covered earlier, there are still a couple of reactions that aren't listed anywhere else.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeatMeatball" Caption="Meatball"/>
  </Box>
  You can make a singular meatball by combining the following reagents:

  -5u Uncooked Animal Proteins
  -5u Flour
  -6u Raw Egg

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodSnackChocolateBar" Caption="Chocolate."/>
  </Box>
  You can make a bar of chocolate by combining the following reagents:

  -4u Cocoa Powder
  -2u Milk
  -2u Sugar

</Document>
