<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  List of Service/Civilian roles and responsibilities by job.

  # Chef

    [bold]V1.01.[/bold] The Chef is not permitted to use the corpses of deceased personnel for meat unless given specific permission from the Chief Medical Officer. Exception is made for changelings and any other executed personnel not slated for Borgifications;

    [bold]V1.02.[/bold] The Chef is permitted to use Ambrosia and other such light narcotics in the production of food; given they are legal.

    [bold]V1.03.[/bold] The Chef must produce at least three (3) dishes of any food within twenty (20) minutes. Failure to do so is to be considered a breach of Standard Operating Procedure;

    [bold]V1.04.[/bold] The Chef is not permitted to leave the kitchen unattended for longer than fifteen (15) minutes if there is no food available for consumption. Exception is made if there are no ingredients, or if the Kitchen is unusable/a hazard zone.

    [bold]V1.05.[/bold] The Chef has full permission to forcefully throw out anyone who climbs over the kitchen table without permission. They are not, however, permitted to do so if the person in question uses the door, or is on an active investigation;

  # Bartender

    [bold]V2.01.[/bold] The Bartender is permitted to use their shotgun on unruly bar patrons in order to throw them out if they are being disruptive. They are not, however, permitted to apply lethal, or near-lethal force;

    [bold]V2.02.[/bold] The Bartender is exempt from legal ramifications when dutifully removing unruly (ie, overtly hostile) patrons from the Bar, provided, of course, they followed Guideline 1;

    [bold]V2.03.[/bold] The Bartender is not permitted to possess regular (ie, lethal) shotgun ammunition. Only beanbag slugs are permitted. Exception is made during major emergencies, such as Nuclear Operatives or Blob Organisms;

    [bold]V2.04.[/bold] The Bartender has full permission to forcefully throw out anyone who climbs over the bar counter without permission, up to and including personnel who may have access to the side windoor. They are not, however, permitted to do so if the person in question uses the door, or is on an active investigation;

  # Botanist

    [bold]V2.01.[/bold] Botanists are permitted to grow experimental plants, presuming they do not distribute it without the express permission of the HOP.

    [bold]V2.02.[/bold] Botanists must provide the Chef with adequate Botanical Supplies, per the Chef’s request, free of charge.

    [bold]V2.03.[/bold] Botanists are not permitted to cause unregulated plantlife to spread outside of Hydroponics or other such designated locations without express permission of the HOP or Captain.

    [bold]V2.04.[/bold] Botanists are not permitted to hand out spatially unstable Botanical Supplies to non-Hydroponics personnel.

    [bold]V2.05.[/bold] Botanists are not permitted to harvest or hand out Amanitin or other such plant/fungi-derived poisons, unless specifically requested by the Head of Security and/or Captain.

    [bold]V2.06.[/bold] Botanists are not permitted the use of a chemical dispenser without the express permission of the Research Director and Head of Personnel.

    [bold]V2.07.[/bold] Botanists are not permitted to carry dangerous plantlife outside Botany, or allow such plantlife to affect outside of Botany.

  # Clown

    [bold]V3.01.[/bold] The Clown is permitted to, and freely exempt from any consequences of, slipping literally anyone, assuming it does not interfere with active Security duty, or in any way endangers other personnel (such as slipping a Paramedic who’s dragging a wounded person to Medbay);

    [bold]V3.02.[/bold] The Clown is not permitted to remove their Clown Shoes or Clown Mask. Exception is made if removing them is truly necessary for the sake of their clowning performance (such as being a satire of bad clowns);

    [bold]V3.03.[/bold] The Clown is not permitted to use or be in possession of Space Lube. Exception is made during major emergencies involving hostile humanoids, whereby use of Space Lube may be condoned to help the crew;

    [bold]V3.04.[/bold] The Clown must legitimately attempt to be funny and/or entertaining at least once every fifteen (15) minutes. A simple pun will suffice. Continuously slipping people for no reason does not constitute humour. The joke is supposed to be funny for everyone;

    [bold]V3.05.[/bold] The Clown is permitted to, and freely exempt from any consequences of, performing any harmless prank that does not directly conflict with the above Guidelines

  # Mime

    [bold]V4.01.[/bold] The Mime is not permitted to talk, under any circumstance whatsoever. A Mime who breaks the Vow of Silence is to be stripped of their rank post haste;

    [bold]V4.02.[/bold] The Mime is permitted to use written words to communicate, either via paper or PDA, but are discouraged from automatically resorting to it when miming will suffice;

    [bold]V4.03.[/bold] The Mime must actually mime something at least once every thirty (30) minutes. Standing against an invisible wall will suffice.

  # Chaplain

    [bold]V5.01.[/bold] The Chaplain is not permitted to execute Bible Healing without consent, unless the person in question is in Critical Condition and there are no doctors available.

    [bold]V5.02.[/bold] The Chaplain may not actively discriminate against any personnel on the grounds that it is a religious tenet of their particular faith;

    [bold]V5.03.[/bold] The Chaplain may freely conduct funerals for non-cloneable/revivable personnel. All funerals should be concluded with the use of the Crematorium.

  # Janitor

    [bold]V6.01.[/bold] The Janitor must promptly respond to any call from the crew for them to clean. Failure to respond within fifteen (15) minutes is to be considered a breach of Standard Operating Procedure;

    [bold]V6.02.[/bold] If the Janitor's work leaves any surface slippery, they are to place wet floor signs, either physical or holographic. During major crises, such as Nuclear Operatives, the Janitor is to refrain from creating any slippery surfaces whatsoever;

    [bold]V6.03.[/bold] The Janitor is not to use Cleaning Foam Grenades as pranking implements. Cleaning Foam Grenades are to be used to clean large surfaces at once, only;

    [bold]V6.04.[/bold] During Viral Outbreaks, the Janitors must don their Biosuit, and focus on cleaning any biological waste, until such a point as the Viral Pathogen is deemed eliminated;

    [bold]V6.05.[/bold] The Janitor may not deploy bear traps anywhere, unless there are actually large wild animals on the station.

    [bold]V6.06.[/bold] The Janitor is responsible for restocking any vending machines on the station. If any one item is out of stock in a machine, a restock should be ordered and be put into the machine.

  # Reporter

    [bold]V7.01.[/bold] The Reporter is permitted to report on any events aboard the station, including those involving Security and Command staff.

    [bold]V7.02.[/bold] The Reporter is not, however, permitted to use slanderous or libelous language or rhetoric when reporting on events such as arrests or imprisonment.

    [bold]V7.03.[/bold] The Reporter should only use positive language when referring to Nanotrasen and Central Command. If unsure about whether or not this should apply to an article, Reporters are advised to fax Centcomm a copy for editorial review.
</Document>
