<Document>
  # Space Law
  Funky Station operates under space law. All crew, passengers, and visitors aboard the station are expected to know and follow these laws (they are fairly common sense, only security and the captain need to know the times).

  ## Treatment Of Prisoners

  Prisoners still have certain rights that must be upheld by law enforcement:

  - Prisoners must be granted adequate medical care. They should also be provided psychiatric and spiritual counselling if requested.
  - Prisoners must be allowed access to communications equipment (Radios) so long as they are not abused.
  - Prisoners must be granted clothing, food, water, shelter and safety. If the brig is no longer safe, confinement must be established in another location.
  - Prisoners must be given access to legal counsel during an interrogation if requested and available.
  - Prisoners must be given their shift mandated PDA after confinement has finished. Unless there is solid proof of PDA tampering, in which case the PDA is to be secured and replaced with a fresh one.
  - Prisoners must be granted freedom of movement, and should not be restrained with handcuffs or other devices after incarceration unless there is an undue risk to life and limb. Similarly, any prisoners held for extended or permanent confinement should be held in the communal brig, and should not be confined to a solitary cell unless they pose a risk to life and limb.

  ## Searches

  A personnel search is a seizure of the objects in a person's backpack, hands, coat, belt, pockets, and hat. If any contraband is found during a search the officer may choose to further the search into a detainment or simply confiscate the restricted items. After the search is conducted all legal items are to be returned to the person.

  A crewmate may legally decline any search conducted without a warrant while the alert level is green. Should be noted that if the alert level is blue or above all personnel searches are legal and no longer require a warrant.

  ## Implantation

  Any prisoner in custody can be subjected to implantation or implant removal procedures, so long as it's within reason. The process of adding an implant should not prolong the detainees sentence, meaning you can not hold them longer to administer the implant, unless stated otherwise. A prisoner can still receive implantation procedures without meeting the circumstances if they give their clear permission.

  [bold]Mind Shields[/bold]: Mind Shields can be administered to any inmate who is clearly brainwashed. Unlike standard implantation, you may hold a prisoner until they are issued a Mind Shield, so long as it's done in a timely fashion. If a suspect refuses to cooperate or the implant fails to function they can be charged with Refusal of Mental Shielding.

  A crewmate can refuse a Mind Shield if they are not imprisoned for committing a crime.

  # Removal

  A suspect can be forced to receive implant removal if there is strong reasonable proof that they have been implanted, such as an officer witnessing them use an implantation device or their biological information being found on a discarded injector. Unlike the implantation procedure a prisoner can have their sentence entirely delayed or extended until they comply with the procedure, as long as security are actively making attempts to preform it. Akin to implanting, if an inmate gives their clear permission, implant removal can proceed without proof.

  ## Sentencing
  All sentencing is to primarily be handled by the Warden, if no Warden is available the HoS is to take over that duty, if there's no HoS it falls onto the highest ranking command member.

  Use common sense and humanity when issuing punishments. You should not always seek out the highest punishment you can, you don't have to always give the maximum time or always look to demote someone. Always take in account the severity and only charge for what is needed for someone to learn their lesson.

  [bold]Accessory, Attempting, And Intention:[/bold] If someone intentionally, knowingly and substantially assists someone in enacting a crime they can be charged with the relevant crimes, such as an engineer giving someone tools, who says they are going to break into an area. Same goes for a clear and solid attempt at a crime, or a person who shows clear intent to act out a crime, such as a syndicate nuclear operative arming a nuke but getting arrested before it goes off, they can still be charged with terrorism. Does not apply to crimes that have an attempted listing already, like attempted murder.

  [bold]Stackable Crimes:[/bold] Crimes are to be considered 'stackable' in the sense that if you charge someone with two or more different crimes, you should combine the times you would give them for each crime.

  [bold]Executions:[/bold] Executions may be authorized by the Captain / acting Captain after a trial has been conducted. Executions may also be approved by CentComm, following formal contact.

  ## Normal Punishments
  - [color=#a4885c]Warning:[/color] For minor crimes, fix the issue, then warn the person not to attempt the crime again. If they still proceed to do it at a later date, a brig time may be better.
  - [color=#a4885c]Confinement:[/color] The typical punishment, being confined in a cell for a temporary amount of time according to the crimes.
  - [color=#a4885c]Demotion:[/color] Entails removing all departmental gear they have on their person and revoking the involved department access off their ID. This requires the captain's or involved department head's approval. Demotions should only be issued if the person pose a threat to their own department or are in a position where they have/can abuse their job's gear to commit further crimes.

  ## Major Punishments
  [color=#a4885c]Permanent Confinement:[/color] Being held in the permanent brig for the entire duration of the shift. A person is eligible for permanent confinement if their timed sentence would exceed 15 minutes. Any persons subject to this punishment are required to be transported in cuffs to CentComm at the end of the shift. A permanent prisoner can not be deprived of anything covered by the section "Treatment Of Prisoners".
  [color=#a4885c]Execution:[/color] A humane way of dealing with extremely unruly crewmates. Within reason, a prisoner who has been given the death sentence may pick how they wish to be killed, common methods are firing line, lethal injection, exile, and high voltage electrocution. Another alternate method of "execution" is the process of placing a staff's mind into a borg, this is allowed so long as it is lawful. Execution can only be issued with the captain's or acting captain's approval; if the HoS is acting captain or there is no acting captain, all heads of staff are to hold a vote on the matter.

  ## Crime Listing
  - [textlink="Crime Listing" link="SpaceLawCrimeList"]
</Document>
