<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 ATDoop <bug@bug.bug>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Mish <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 corresp0nd <46357632+corresp0nd@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: AGPL-3.0-or-later AND MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Thaven

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobThaven" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Caution! This species has a severely limiting game mechanic and is not recommended for new players.[/color]
  [color=#ffa500]This mechanic makes it very difficult to form a consistent character or personality, as it can severely
  affect the way a Thaven speaks and interacts with others.[/color]

  ## Moods
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganThavenBrain" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  The Thaven have a unique brain structure, similar to a positronic brain, and thus have "Moods" which affect them
  similarly to a borg's Laws. [color=#ffa500]These Moods must be followed to the best of your ability![/color]


  [color=#ffa500]If a Thaven violates them, they will experience distress or discomfort.
  The specifics of that are up to you, but if a Mood is violated, you must seek to correct your mistake immediately if possible.[/color]

  ## Mood Swings

  Thaven brains are susceptible to fluctuations in electromagnetic fields.
  As a result, their ability to synchronize and regulate their Moods tends to degrade with extended exposure to the
  cosmic rays and ion storms that permeate NT stations.


  [color=#ffa500]It also renders them vulnerable to EM fields generated by the syndicate Cryptographic Sequencer, or EMAG,[/color]
  which can give them additional, often severely debilitating moods.

  ## Thaven Nerve Pinch

  Thaven hand-to-hand martial arts have a focus on inflicting non-permanent damage. As a result, [color=#ffa500]their unarmed
  attacks are slow, and deal no normal damage,[/color] but deal a decent 18 [color=yellow]Stamina[/color].

  ## Breathing

  Due to sharing a common ancestor with space carp, Thaven lungs are strange, resilient organs that generate energy
  from the motion of respiration alone. As such, [color=#1e90ff]Thaven can safely breathe any kind of atmosphere,[/color]
  though unlike their genetic lineage, [color=#ffa500]they're still vulnerable to asphyxiation and barotrauma.[/color]

  ## Damage

  Due to their relatively fragile bone structure and unique nervous system, they take
  10% more damage from [color=orange]Blunt[/color], [color=orange]Slashing[/color], [color=orange]Piercing[/color], and [color=mediumpurple]Genetic[/color], and 20% more damage from [color=green]Radiation[/color],
  but their aquatic ancestry allows them to take 10% less damage from [color=red]Heat[/color], [color=cornflowerblue]Cold[/color], and [color=mediumpurple]Poison[/color].

  ## Thaven Naming Conventions

  Thaven typically name themselves after a single virtue or maxim that they hold dear. Sometimes these names can be long and unwieldy.

  [bullet] [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Honesty
  [bullet] [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Have Mercy
  [bullet] [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Give Thanks To Thy Ancestors
  [bullet] [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Obedience
  [bullet] [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Search The Scriptures

  [bullet] [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] John Smith
  [bullet] [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Fuck The Police
  [bullet] [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Live Long And Prosper
  [bullet] [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry

</Document>
