<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Errant <35878406+Errant-4@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 JIPDawg <51352440+JIPDawg@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 MilenVolf <63782763+MilenVolf@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Diona

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDiona" Caption=""/>
  </Box>


  Diona are an alien species of sentient plants, with a wide and varied evolutionary history and countless ancestors in
  common vegetation, trees, flowers, etc.

  ## Diona Physiology
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FloraTree" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Diona blood is a sort of sap excreted by their wooden flesh, and it can't be metabolized from Iron. Furthermore,
  being plants, Weed Killer can poison a Diona, whereas Robust Harvest can heal them in moderation. Overdosing on
  Robust Harvest will cause a Diona to grow out of control, turning into an immobile tree. Cutting down the tree will
  restore the Diona to their usual state.

  Having no real "feet", Diona cannot wear shoes. Fortunately, they are not slowed by Kudzu.

  Diona also tend to get hungry and thirsty significantly slower than other species, and asphyxiate half as fast.

  ## Diona Nymphs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  After death, a Diona can voluntarily destroy their own body, releasing their "internal organs" as three Nymphs,
  with the player taking control of the Brain Nymph.
  It can talk but has no hands or inventory, and can't do much.

  After 10 minutes, a Nymph can reform into a whole Diona. This will be a new randomised body with a random name,
  and there will be little to no evidence beyond their word about who they were before.

  ## Damage
  Diona take 30% less [color=orange]Blunt[/color] damage and 20% less [color=orange]Slashing[/color] damage, but 50% more [color=red]Heat[/color] damage,
  20% more [color=red]Shock[/color] damage, and they can easily catch on fire when receiving enough Heat damage.

  ## Diona Naming Conventions

  Diona typically have nature themed, Noun of Noun style names.

  [bullet] The Blossom of Bravery

  [bullet] The Elder of Nobility

  [bullet] The Canyon of Balance

</Document>
