<Document>
  # Mail Clerk SOP

  [bold]1.[/bold] [color=#F52900]🟥[/color] Keep the mail teleporter on only as much as you can handle. If mail gets overwhelming, turn it off until the majority of mail has been opened, so that less fines are issued to the Cargo Department;

  [bold]2.[/bold][color=#F52900]🟥[/color] Mail Clerks are responsible for ensuring priority mail, with the yellow stripe, are delivered as soon as possible in order to avoid fines and maximize profits for Cargo;

  [bold]3.[/bold][color=#0066F5]🔶[/color] Mail Clerks are responsible for keeping the mail statistics at 90% of packages opened or higher. When new packages arrive, there will be a temporary dip, but if the statistics drops before 65% then IAA is free to investigate. If IAA determines there is not a reasonable cause for the low amount of opened packages then fines may be issued. Factors out of the Mail Clerk’s control should not be counted against the Department;

  [bold]4.[/bold][color=#0066F5]🔶[/color] If there is no one at the desk when the Mail Clerk arrives at a department, they may leave any packages for said department’s staff on the departmental desk. If the mail is left in this manner, the Clerk must make sure to use the intercom to alert the receiving department of the delivery;

  [bold]5.[/bold][color=#0066F5]🔶[/color] If a specific department has over 75% of their packages unopened after delivery, the Mail Clerk may request the Quartermaster halt all orders from that department until the packages are opened. The IAA should be informed by the Mail Clerk in writing, at the same time as the request is made. Any mail from workers in cryosleep should be returned to Cargo and not counted against as unopened;

  [bold]6.[/bold][color=#0CBF00]⚙[/color] Mail Clerks should wear appropriate clothing so as to be recognized;

  [bold]7.[/bold][color=#0CBF00]⚙[/color]Mail Clerks are allowed to order one mail cart without the Quartermaster’s approval, as long as Cargo has more than 10,000 spesos at the time the order is approved;
</Document>
