<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tay <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Quartermaster SOP

[bold]1.[/bold] [color=#F52900]游린[/color] The Quartermaster is part of command must also follow the Command SOP;

[bold]2.[/bold][color=#F52900]游린[/color] The Quartermaster is responsible for making sure no security items are ordered except by security staff, except during red alert when command has authorized the crew to arm. If the QM determines there to be sufficient threat to the station during red alert but before crew is authorized to arm, the QM may order security items as long as they are delivered directly to security immediately after pickup;

  [bold]3.[/bold][color=#F52900]游린[/color] The Quartermaster is responsible for ensuring that any orders involving security or command items are not lost in transit. Delegating pickup and delivery is fine, but the QM should know who is picking up the items in addition to staying up to date on the progress of the delivery;

  [bold]4.[/bold][color=#F52900]游린[/color] The Quartermaster is responsible for ensuring all departments have their needs met. This includes making sure that salvaged materials are distributed amongst all departments, as well as making sure that orders are being handled in a timely manner. Salvaged materials are to be distributed proactively especially to Medical, Security, and Engineering;

  [bold5.[/bold] [color=#F52900]游린[/color] The Quartermaster is responsible for all lottery crates that are ordered. Any lottery crates are to be ordered by the QM, and opened by the QM. Any lottery crates ordered by other departments must be brought to their respective departments, before being unlocked. If the QM is not available, another command member must be assigned to this responsibility;

  [bold]6.[/bold][color=#0066F5]游댰[/color] The Quartermaster is responsible for making sure all employees in the department are following SOP. If authorizing an SOP deviation, the QM should write an explanation, stamp it, and keep it in a folder in their office in case of an audit. Destruction of the documents counts as failure to fulfill this responsibility;

  [bold]7.[/bold][color=#0CBF00]丘뗕/color] The Quartermaster is responsible for ensuring that confirmed orders reach their intended recipient within 15 minutes of the order arriving on the Automated Trade Station
</Document>
