<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tay <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Salvage Specialist SOP

[bold]1.[/bold][color=#F52900]🟥[/color] Salvage Specialists must send 60 Steel, Plasma, Gold, Silver, Glass, and Uranium by 00:30:00 shift time. It is recommended to take no more than 6 minutes to gather gear and the shuttle, so you can mine 4 magnet asteroids by this time. If the magnet does not provide a particular resource by this time, the QM must be informed of this fact;

  [bold]2.[/bold][color=#F52900]🟥[/color] Salvage is not allowed to hoard materials. All mined and/or processed ore, diamonds, crystals, should be sent to cargo to be distributed. If Salvage needs something specific made for their work, send the request through the Quartermaster and/or Research Director, to make sure it is prioritized;

[bold]3.[/bold][color=#F52900]🟥[/color] If a report of anyone drifting in space is heard on comms, the Salvage team must return to their ship as soon as possible, and determine if they will need to assist in the rescue. As the most experienced and equipped team for space travel, Salvage is required to be ready and to assist in rescue operations if called on. Failure to respond to requests on comms, or refusal to assist when able, will be considered for prevention of revival charges if the Magistrate or CC agree. These charges cannot be laid if the Quartermaster believes Salvage did what they could to help;

  [bold]4.[/bold][color=#0066F5]🔶[/color] When looting wrecks, Salvage Specialists must keep other departments in mind. Cloning machines, bluespace items, RTGs, are examples of things that should be brought back to support other departments;

  [bold]5.[/bold][color=#0066F5]🔶[/color] Salvage Specialists must have a fulton beacon and linked fultons set up in the cargo bay at all times. The spare fulton beacon from the Equipment Vendor can be used as the Specialists desire;

  [bold]6.[/bold][color=#0066F5]🔶[/color] Salvage Specialists are permitted to use weapons they find in self-defense, but must report weapons and contraband found to the Quartermaster and obtain a permit for the reported items. If a weapon or item that is considered contraband is found on a salvage specialist or their ship without a permit, it is considered a SOP violation. If there is neither a permit nor evidence of the item being reported, it may be escalated to a crime under Space Law; Non-Departmental gear is not considered contraband in this, as Salvage Specialists may need to use abnormal equipment in their work (e.g. combat gloves aren’t contraband, but Blood-Red Combat gloves are);

  [bold]7.[/bold][color=#0CBF00]⚙[/color] The salvage shuttle must be kept clean and free of spills, debris, refuse, etc;

  [bold]8.[/bold][color=#0CBF00]⚙[/color] Salvage teams must check in with the Quartermaster every 30 minutes and before they FTL on expeditions, to provide updates on their current status and notable discoveries;
</Document>
