<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tay <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Internal Affairs Agent SOP

[bold]1.[/bold] Internal Affairs Agents are to ensure that Standard Operating Procedure is being properly followed, and to contact the relevant Head of Staff when it is not;

[bold]2.[/bold] Internal Affairs Agents are to follow the following chain of escalation should their reports be ignored, or they feel a judgement is incorrect: Relevant [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color] -> [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color] -> [color=#009100]NanoTrasen Representative[/color] -> [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color] -> [color=#009100]Central Command[/color];

[bold]3.[/bold] Internal Affairs Agents are only to concern themselves with matters of [textlink="Space Law" link="SpaceLaw"] if there is no [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color] and no [color=#009100]NanoTrasen Representative[/color] aboard the station, or if the [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color] or [color=#009100]NanoTrasen Representative[/color] give them orders to do so, or if [color=#009100]Central Command[/color] contacts them directly and requests that they do so;

[bold]4.[/bold] Internal Affairs Agents must be granted permission from the presiding Judge (i.e. the [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color] or [color=#009100]NanoTrasen Representative[/color]) to serve as legal representation for personnel in any court hearing. Internal Affairs Agents may only serve as legal representation for personnel if another Internal Affairs Agent is capable of assuming the role of prosecution, and if no Lawyer is available. Internal Affairs Agents must also request permission from any potential client before serving as their legal representative, as said client may choose to either represent themselves, or request someone else;

[bold]5.[/bold] Internal Affairs Agents may administer class 1 penalties for misconduct concerning Standard Operating Procedure after first receiving approval from the [color=#009100]NanoTrasen Representative[/color] or [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color]. They may only administer penalties for misconduct concerning misinterpretation of space law in the absense of a [color=#009100]NanoTrasen Representative[/color] and [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color], and may [bold]never[/bold] administer class 2 or 3 penalties even when serving as the only [color=#009100]Central Command[/color] staff on station.

[bold]6.[/bold] Internal Affairs Agents are permitted to carry their flash and their administrative sunglasses;

## Internal Affairs Agent OOC Rules

[bold]1.[/bold] You are a non combatant advisor, and should not be participating in combat except in the case of self defense.

[bold]2.[/bold] You have a lot of power as an Internal Affairs Agent. Abuse of this trust will result in a permanent, non appealable role ban from CC roles. Your job is to make the round more fun through interesting role play, not just be an authoritarian power tripper.
</Document>
