<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tay <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Magistrate SOP

[bold]1.[/bold] The Magistrate holds the ultimate punitive authority on station. When exercising this authority the Magistrate is directly exercising the will of [color=#009100]Central Command[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] The Magistrate may overrule anyone, save [color=#009100]Central Command[/color], in all matters concerning Space Law.

[bold]3.[/bold] The Magistrate is to ensure that station resources are not wasted on trials that are frivolous in nature or whos outcomes are a forgone conclusion. Magistrates have authority to summarily sentence and pass judgement in such cases, but should ensure due diligence has been enforced in regards to the collection of evidence;

[bold]4.[/bold] The Magistrate is [bold]not[/bold] above [textlink="Space Law" link="SpaceLaw"] and may not make rulings in matters concerning their own potential misconduct;

[bold]5.[/bold] The Magistrate is to ensure that the [color=#009100]NanoTrasen Representative[/color] and [color=#009100]Internal Affairs Agents[/color] under their command are responding appropriately to matters of and misconduct regarding Standard Operating Procedure.

[bold]6.[/bold] The Magistrate, outside the context of a trial, should only concern themselves with crimes that either have fuzzy evidence, require careful deliberation of circumstances, or have been horrendously mishandled;

[bold]7.[/bold] The Magistrate may administer class 1, 2, and 3 penalties for misconduct concerning the misinterpretation of [textlink="Space Law" link="SpaceLaw"]. They should consult with the [color=#009100]NanoTrasen Representative[/color] before administering penalties for misconduct concerning standard operating procedure, but have authority to administer up to class 3 penalties for those breaches as well.

[bold]8.[/bold] The Magistrate is permitted to carry their flash;

## Magistrate OOC Rules
[textlink="Act and behave within the spirit of the Job you have been assigned" link="RuleC15"]
</Document>
