<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tay <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Nanotrasen Representative SOP

[bold]1.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative is to ensure that every Department is following Standard Operating Procedure, up to and including the respective [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color]. If a [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color] is not available for a Department, the NanoTrasen Representative must ensure that the [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color] appoints an [color=#1b67a5]Acting Head of Staff[/color] for said Department;

[bold]2.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative must attempt to resolve any breach of Standard Operating Procedure locally before contacting [color=#009100]Central Command[/color].

[bold]3.[/bold] In the absense of a [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color], the NanoTrasen Representative must ensure that space law is being adequately followed and enforced.

[bold]4.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative may administer class 1 and 2 penalties for misconduct concerning Standard Operating Procedure. They may only administer penalties for misconduct concerning misinterpretation of [textlink="Space Law" link="SpaceLaw"] in the absense of a [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color], and may never administer class 3 penalties even when there is no [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color];

[bold]5.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative must follow the directions of the [color=#cb0000]Magistrate[/color] and defer to their judgement in matters not concerning standard operating procedure, but should advocate their stance firmly in the case of disagreements, and escalate to [color=#009100]Central Command[/color] directly if they feel there has been wrongdoing;

[bold]6.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative is permitted to carry their flash and a blade-cane, or a stun baton if the blade-cane is lost;

## Nanotrasen Representative OOC Rules

[bold]1.[/bold] You are not a Mega Captain. You are really only on station as an advisor, and should generally only exersize your authority in regard to matters other than SOP in extreme circumstances, or obvious cases of wrongdoing.

[bold]2.[/bold] You are a non combatant advisor, and should not be participating in combat except in the case of self defense.

[bold]3.[/bold] You have a lot of power as the NanoTrasen Representative. Abuse of this trust will result in a permanent, non appealable role ban from CC roles. Your job is to make the round more fun through interesting role play, not just be an authoritarian power tripper.
</Document>
