<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 kbarkevich <24629810+kbarkevich@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Detective

## Code Green

[bold]1.[/bold] The Detective is permitted to assist [color=#cb0000]Security Officers[/color] with all Patrol Duties. This includes stops, searches, and arrests as per the current Alert Code. They should, however, prioritize investigations and the collection of forensic evidence;

[bold]2.[/bold] The Detective is to follow all Standard Operating Procedures as outlined by the Security Officer SOP in regard to stops, searches and arrests as per the current Alert Code;

[bold]3.[/bold] The Detective may carry their revolver and spare ammunition;

[bold]4.[/bold] The Detective may carry a fully kitted out security belt;

[bold]5.[/bold] The Detective is permitted to wear non-Security clothing with permission from the [color=#1b67a5]Head of Security[/color] for the purpose of undercover investigations. They are, however, expected to carry their [color=#cb0000]Security ID[/color] on their person at all times;

[bold]6.[/bold] When not undercover, the Detective must follow the same guidelines as [color=#cb0000]Security Officers[/color] for attire, with the exception that their own assigned attire is also acceptable for any of the attire mentioned for [color=#cb0000]Security Officers[/color].

## Code Blue

[bold]1.[/bold] All Guidelines carry over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] The Detective may pull aside any suspect for an interrogation during the course of their time in Processing. If the suspect requests legal representation during interrogation, the Detective is required to permit it only if the suspect is charged with a Tier III crime or greater. No detainee is to be held for longer than ten (10) minutes in Processing if no evidence against them is readily available.

## Code Red

[bold]1.[/bold] Guidelines 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5 carry over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] Guidelines 2 and 3 carry over from [color=darkblue]Code Blue[/color];

[bold]3.[/bold] The Detective is permitted to carry around any weapons or equipment available in the Armory, at the [color=#cb0000]Warden[/color]'s discretion, but never more than one at a time. Exception is made for station ending emergencies or terrorism.
</Document>
