<Document>
  # EoC: Enemy of the Corporation

  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"Enemies of the Corporation include but are not limited to: The Syndicate (through secret agents, boarding parties, and brainwashing specialists), Changelings, Heretics, and other intelligent hostile forms of life that seek to cause major damage to the station and or crew."[/italic][/color]
  </Box>

  Example Circumstances:
  - [bold]Execution/Imprisonment[/bold] - If an Enemy of the Corporation has not committed any capital crimes they are to be placed in Permanent Imprisonment (Permabrig/Solitary/Labor Camp) without exception. Otherwise, Execution is permitted at the discretion of the Captain, with approval from CentComm. Leniency is granted during a Red Alert.
  - [bold]Uncontainable EoCs[/bold] - Heretics, or any other Enemies of the Corporation that cannot be contained safely in the Brig, are to be executed irrespective of their crimes. Head Revolutionaries are to be executed as soon as they are positively identified. Being a space-proof species does not constitute being impossible to contain.
  - [bold]Changelings[/bold] - All changelings are to be considered hostile alien lifeforms and a direct threat to all personnel. All changelings are to be killed on sight and immediately cremated. Forensic evidence and/or direct testimony from Mindshielded personnel is necessary to establish proof they are a changeling. Personnel who provide false testimony are to be charged with Murder if the supposed changeling is killed and attempted murder if it is not.
  - [bold]Surrendering EoCs[/bold] - Enemies of the Corporation that willingly turn themselves into Security of their own accord are to be kept in Permanent Imprisonment so long as they aren't impossible to contain. Defectors and captives are to be transported to Central Command via the Crew Transfer Shuttle; they are to be treated as dangerous enemies, but also protected from retribution and provided for.

  Situations that warrant the use of Deadly Force are few and far between. In the vast majority of cases, Security is expected to use non-lethal tools which are generally more effective in defusing situations. It is preferable to capture personnel through non-lethal means unless a situation warrants otherwise. Failure to adhere to this principle will result in discipline, demotion, and even job bans.

  There are, however, circumstances where deadly force is permissible:

  # Non-EoC’s / Petty Criminals
  - Non-EoC’s and Petty Criminals such as thieves, rioters, and former revolutionaries should be revived / deconverted as soon as possible.
  - Do not resuscitate orders cannot be issued for such petty criminals, and if lethal force is used on such criminals, charges against them are recommended to be dropped, as being crit / dead is punishment enough.

  # Lethals Authorized
  [bold]Post-Combat Treatment / Revival Required[/bold]
  - Armed and Dangerous Individuals
  - May include people with stun weapons, lethal weapons, etc.
  - Multiple Assailants
  - Individuals Possessing Explosives
  - (Grenades, welding fuel tanks, etc.)
  - Revolutionaries
  - Armory Trespassers

  # Lethals Recommended
  [bold]Posthumous Revival Potentially Required[/bold]
  - Heretics
  - Holoparasite Users
  - Hostile Hardsuits
  - Non-Crew
  - Ash Walkers (ghouls), abominable creatures
  - Uncontainable sentient beings

  # Lethals Authorized
  [bold]Kill on Sight[/bold]
  - Ascended Heretics
  - Nuclear Operatives
  - Perma Escapees (when outside the Permabrig)
  - Exogenous Threats
  - Bluespace Entities
  - Revolutionary Heads
  - Abominations
</Document>
