<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 kbarkevich <24629810+kbarkevich@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Head of Security SOP

## Code Green

[bold]1.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to carry out arrests under the same conditions as their [color=#cb0000]Security Officers[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to carry a fully kitted security belt and a standard issue pistol. While permitted to carry their unique X-01 Multiphase gun, they are discouraged from doing so for safety concerns, and should keep it on Stun/Disable;

[bold]3.[/bold] The Head of Security is required to permit a trial in the circumstances outlined in the [textlink="Legal SOP" link="LegalSOP"] section, and is likewise required to permit the suspect access to confidential meetings with their chosen legal representative at any time during their sentence. The suspect's brig time should not be advanced during confidential meetings with a legal representative, and should be paused until such a time as the suspect has returned to their cell;

[bold]4.[/bold] The Head of Security is required to permit a suspect access to legal representation [italic]during interrogation[/italic] only in cases where the suspect is charged with a Tier III crime or greater;

[bold]5.[/bold] The Head of Security must follow the same guidelines as the [color=#cb0000]Warden[/color] for Armory equipment, portable flashers and deployable barriers;

[bold]6.[/bold] The Head of Security is [bold]not[/bold] permitted to collect equipment from the Armory to carry on their person;

[bold]7.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to either use their regular coat, or armored trench coat;

[bold]8.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to wear their unique gas mask;

[bold]9.[/bold] The Head of Security may [bold]not[/bold] overrule established sentences, unless further evidence is brought to light or the prisoner in question attempts to escape;

[bold]10.[/bold] The Head of Security must follow the same guidelines as [color=#cb0000]Security Officers[/color] for attire, with the exception that their own assigned attire is also acceptable for any of the attire mentioned for Security Officers;

[bold]11.[/bold] The Head of Security is encouraged to follow the [textlink="Security Rules of Conduct" link="RulesOfConduct"], as this sets a proper example for [color=#cb0000]Cadets[/color] and establishes good trust with the public.

## Code Blue

[bold]1.[/bold] All Guidelines carry over from Code Green. In regard to Guideline 2, the Head of Security is now encouraged to carry their unique Energy Gun.

[bold]2.[/bold] In regard to guideline 5, leniency may be granted in order to ensure Command and other important members of the station are protected.

## Code Red

[bold]1.[/bold] Guidelines 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 9, 10, and 11 are carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] The Head of Security is [bold]not[/bold] required to permit a trial during states of emergency. However, the Head of Security is still required to permit the suspect access to confidential meetings with their chosen legal representative at any time during their sentence, and the suspect's brig time should not be advanced during these confidential meetings.

[bold]3.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to take whatever equipment they require from the Armory, provided they leave enough equipment for the rest of the [color=#cb0000]Security force;

[bold]4.[/bold] The Head of Security is [bold]required[/bold] to make a Station Announcement regarding the nature of the confirmed threat that caused Code Red.
</Document>
