<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Rules of Conduct

  At Nanotrasen, we trust our officers to act with the utmost dignity reflecting their positions. This policy outlines the rules of conduct our valiant Security force strive to uphold every day.

  [bold]1.[/bold] Security Officers shall not violate the Law which they uphold.

  [bold]2.[/bold] Security Officers shall not act against the interests of the Nanotrasen Corporation.

  [bold]3.[/bold] Security Officers shall act with dignity and respect towards other employees.

  [bold]4.[/bold] Security Officers shall ensure the welfare of any detainees in their care.

  [bold]5.[/bold] Security Officers shall strive to protect Nanotrasen property, including employees.

  [bold]6.[/bold] Security Officers shall not solicit or accept any bribes from any person or organization.

  [bold]7.[/bold] Security Officers shall not falsely report a crime.

  [bold]8.[/bold] Security Officers shall not be incompetent.

  [bold]9.[/bold] Security Officers shall not drink to the point of being intoxicated.

  [bold]10.[/bold] Security Officers shall not unduly interfere with station productivity.

  [bold]11.[/bold] Security Officers shall not be absent from duty assignment.

  [bold]12.[/bold] Security Officers shall not be critical or talk negatively about other Nanotrasen security officers or any member of Command while on-duty.

  [bold]13.[/bold] Security Officers shall not join a union or entertain the idea of a union.

  [bold]14.[/bold] Security Officers shall not hold a cigarette, cigar, or pipe in mouth while in uniform and in official contact with the public.

  [bold]15.[/bold] Security Officers shall not associate or fraternize with any person to have been convicted of any crime, excluding violations that resulted in a warning.

  [bold]16.[/bold] Security Officers shall not give an opinion on any punishment to a crime, or whether the law should be enforced or not.

  Failure to follow these Rules of Conduct may result in disciplinary action, or in termination, depending on the severity of the violation. All disciplinary actions or terminations may be made at the discretion of the Head of Security or the Captain.
</Document>
