<Document>
  # Security Training Manual

  Welcome to your new job, officer!

  We at Nanotrasen praise your dedication to safety and willingness to do anything for the wellbeing of the corporation.
  Below, you will find training material for your new position.

  The following material is available for your reference, training, and use.
  The information is designed to assist Officers in their professional development.
  Please use the material to expand your understanding, enhance your professional knowledge, and to further your career.

  Please also remember that all of this material is [bold]confidential,[/bold] as per the NDA you signed on employment.
  Failure to comply with the terms of your employment will be met with swift legal action.

  ## Section I. Corporate Secrets

  As one of our field officers, you are primarily in charge of maintaining the wellbeing of the station's crew and ensuring that the crew properly performs their job.
  You are to ensure that the crew is kept in line and focused on this task, and you are also to ensure the crew's safety from any external forces.
  These forces may range from xenofauna (snakes, spiders, carp, dragons, or slimes) or other corporations, factions or individuals who may want to cause harm to Nanotrasen or its crew.

  One of the primary organizations who may target the station is the Syndicate. The crew is aware that they exist, however, they are instructed that Nanotrasen will take care of any potential issues with it.
  You, as one of our officers, are the force that deals with any targeted attacks. The crew should not be involved in any capacity. Similarly, the crew is not to know that their immediate wellbeing is in danger, in the event of Syndicate espionage.
  In the event of a targeted attack, you should resolve it to the best of your ability without fear mongering within the crew.

  The crew may be discontent with their current working conditions. You are, of course, to ensure that the cause of this dissatisfaction is not due to unsafe conditions.
  Consider working together with your command members to placate crew members by doing things like throwing a pizza party.
  However, this dissatisfaction may become unmanageable and cause the crew to consider a unionization, or even a revolt.
  In this event, the source of said discontent is likely caused by an outside force and can not be resolved through de-escalation. Refer to your command members for more instruction.

  You may come across specific items or events that are unexplainable by natural means. These items may be magical in nature, ranging from eldritch, bluespace or hematological magic. Refer to your command members for more instruction.

  Some xenofauna may be much more disastrous, inorganic, or unexplainable than the common space fauna. Refer to your command members for further instruction.

  Some diseases may be much more concerning than the average space flu; cooperate with the Chief Medical Officer for any further instruction.
</Document>
