<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 kbarkevich <24629810+kbarkevich@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Security Officers / Cadets

## Code Green

[bold]1.[/bold] Security Officers are encouraged to act in accordance with the [textlink="Security Rules of Conduct" link="RulesOfConduct"] before engaging with any member of the public.

[bold]2.[/bold] Security Officers are required to state the reasons behind an arrest before any further action is taken. Exception is made if the suspect refuses to stop;

[bold]3.[/bold] Security Officers must attempt to bring all suspects or witnesses to the Brig without handcuffing or incapacitating them. Should the suspect not cooperate, the officer may proceed as usual;

[bold]4.[/bold] No weapons are to be brandished until the suspect attempts to run away or becomes actively hostile;

[bold]5.[/bold] Security Officers may [bold]not[/bold] demand access to the interior of other Departments during regular patrols. However, asking for access from the [color=#9fed58]Head of Personnel[/color] is still acceptable;

[bold]6.[/bold] Security Officers are [bold]not[/bold] permitted to have weapons drawn during regular patrols;

[bold]7.[/bold] Security Officers are [bold]not[/bold] permitted to conduct searches, unless there is reasonable evidence/suspicion that the person in question has committed a crime. Any further searches require a warrant from the [color=#1b67a5]Head of Security[/color] or [color=#1b67a5]Captain[/color];

[bold]8.[/bold] Security Officers are required to wear their uniform in accordance with the [textlink="Security Rules of Conduct" link="RulesOfConduct"];

[bold]9.[/bold] Security Officers are discouraged from entering maintenance without a valid reason. If they must enter maintenance for one reason or another, it is highly recommended that they do so with a partner.

## Code Blue

[bold]1.[/bold] Guidelines 1, 2, 4 and 8 are carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] Security Officers are permitted to carry around any weapons or equipment available in the Armory, at the [color=#cb0000]Warden[/color]'s discretion, but never more than one at a time. Exception is made for severe emergencies, such as terrorism;

[bold]3.[/bold] Security Officers are permitted to carry weapons in hand during regular patrols, although this is not advised;

[bold]4.[/bold] Security Officers are permitted to present weapons during arrests;

[bold]5.[/bold] Security Officers may demand entry to specific Departments during regular patrols;

[bold]6.[/bold] Security Officers may randomly search crewmembers, but are not allowed to apply any degree of force unless said crewmember acts overtly hostile. Crew who refuse to be searched may be stunned and cuffed for the search;

[bold]7.[/bold] Security Officers are permitted to leave prisoners cuffed should they act hostile.

## Code Red

[bold]1.[/bold] Guidelines 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7 are carried over from Code Blue. Guideline 8 is carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

[bold]2.[/bold] Security Officers may arrest crewmembers with no stated reason if there is evidence they are involved in criminal activities;

[bold]3.[/bold] Security Officers may forcefully relocate crewmembers to their respective Departments if necessary.
</Document>
