<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 kbarkevich <24629810+kbarkevich@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  Here is a list of all the SOP documents for Security.

  # Head of Security SOP

  ## Code Green

  [bold]S1.01.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to carry out arrests under the same conditions as their Security Officers;

  [bold]S1.02.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to carry a fully kitted security belt and a standard issue pistol. While permitted to carry their unique X-01 Multiphase gun, they are discouraged from doing so for safety concerns, and should keep it on Stun/Disable;

  [bold]S1.03.[/bold] The Head of Security is required to permit a trial in the circumstances outlined in the [textlink="Legal SOP" link="LegalSOP"] section, and is likewise required to permit the suspect access to confidential meetings with their chosen legal representative at any time during their sentence. The suspect's brig time should not be advanced during confidential meetings with a legal representative, and should be paused until such a time as the suspect has returned to their cell;

  [bold]S1.04.[/bold] The Head of Security is required to permit a suspect access to legal representation [italic]during interrogation[/italic] only in cases where the suspect is charged with a Tier III crime or greater;

  [bold]S1.05.[/bold] The Head of Security must follow the same guidelines as the Warden for Armory equipment, portable flashers and deployable barriers;

  [bold]S1.06.[/bold] The Head of Security is not permitted to collect equipment from the Armory to carry on their person;

  [bold]S1.07.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to either use their regular coat, or armored trench coat;

  [bold]S1.08.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to wear their unique gas mask;

  [bold]S1.09.[/bold] The Head of Security may not overrule established sentences, unless further evidence is brought to light or the prisoner in question attempts to escape;

  [bold]S1.10.[/bold] The Head of Security must follow the same guidelines as Security Officers for attire, with the exception that their own assigned attire is also acceptable for any of the attire mentioned for Security Officers;

  [bold]S1.11.[/bold] The Head of Security is encouraged to follow the Security Rules of Conduct, as this sets a proper example for Cadets and establishes good trust with the public.

  ## Code Blue

  [bold]S1.01B.[/bold] All Guidelines carry over from Code Green. In regard to Guideline 2, the Head of Security is now encouraged to carry their unique Energy Gun.

  [bold]S1.02B.[/bold] In regard to guideline 5, leniency may be granted in order to ensure Command and other important members of the station are protected.

  ## Code Red

  [bold]S1.01R.[/bold] Guidelines 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 9, 10, and 11 are carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

  [bold]S1.02R.[/bold] The Head of Security is not required to permit a trial during states of emergency. However, the Head of Security is still required to permit the suspect access to confidential meetings with their chosen legal representative at any time during their sentence, and the suspect's brig time should not be advanced during these confidential meetings.

  [bold]S1.03R.[/bold] The Head of Security is permitted to take whatever equipment they require from the Armory, provided they leave enough equipment for the rest of the Security force;

  [bold]S1.04R.[/bold] The Head of Security is required to make a Station Announcement regarding the nature of the confirmed threat that caused Code Red.

  # Security Officers / Cadets

  ## Code Green

  [bold]S2.01.[/bold] Security Officers are encouraged to act in accordance with the Security Rules of Conduct before engaging with any member of the public.

  [bold]S2.02.[/bold] Security Officers are required to state the reasons behind an arrest before any further action is taken. Exception is made if the suspect refuses to stop;

  [bold]S2.03.[/bold] Security Officers must attempt to bring all suspects or witnesses to the Brig without handcuffing or incapacitating them. Should the suspect not cooperate, the officer may proceed as usual;

  [bold]S2.04.[/bold] No weapons are to be brandished until the suspect attempts to run away or becomes actively hostile;

  [bold]S2.05.[/bold] Security Officers may not demand access to the interior of other Departments during regular patrols. However, asking for access from the Head of Personnel is still acceptable;

  [bold]S2.06.[/bold] Security Officers are not permitted to have weapons drawn during regular patrols;

  [bold]S2.07.[/bold] Security Officers are not permitted to conduct searches, unless there is reasonable evidence/suspicion that the person in question has committed a crime. Any further searches require a warrant from the Head of Security or Captain;

  [bold]S2.08.[/bold] Security Officers are required to wear their uniform in accordance with the Security Rules of Conduct.

  ## Code Blue

  [bold]S2.01B.[/bold] Guidelines 1, 2, 4 and 8 are carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

  [bold]S2.02B.[/bold] Security Officers are permitted to carry around any weapons or equipment available in the Armory, at the Warden's discretion, but never more than one at a time. Exception is made for severe emergencies, such as Nuclear Operatives;

  [bold]S2.03B.[/bold] Security Officers are permitted to carry weapons in hand during regular patrols, although this is not advised;

  [bold]S2.04B.[/bold] Security Officers are permitted to present weapons during arrests;

  [bold]S2.05B.[/bold] Security Officers may demand entry to specific Departments during regular patrols;

  [bold]S2.06B.[/bold] Security Officers may randomly search crewmembers, but are not allowed to apply any degree of force unless said crewmember acts overtly hostile. Crew who refuse to be searched may be stunned and cuffed for the search;

  [bold]S2.07B.[/bold] Security Officers are permitted to leave prisoners cuffed should they act hostile.

  ## Code Red

  [bold]S2.01R.[/bold] Guidelines 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7 are carried over from Code Blue. Guideline 8 is carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

  [bold]S2.02R.[/bold] Security Officers may arrest crewmembers with no stated reason if there is evidence they are involved in criminal activities;

  [bold]S2.03R.[/bold] Security Officers may forcefully relocate crewmembers to their respective Departments if necessary.

  # Warden

  ## Code Green

  [bold]S3.01.[/bold] The Warden may not perform arrests if there are Security Officers active;

  [bold]S3.02.[/bold] The Warden must conduct a thorough search of every prisoner’s belongings, including pockets, PDA slots, any coat pockets and suit storage slots;

  [bold]S3.03.[/bold] The Warden is required to permit a trial in the circumstances outlined in the [textlink="Legal SOP" link="LegalSOP"] section, and is likewise required to permit the suspect access to confidential meetings with their chosen legal representative at any time during their sentence. The suspect's brig time should not be advanced during confidential meetings with a legal representative, and should be paused until such a time as the suspect has returned to their cell;

  [bold]S3.04.[/bold] The Warden is required to permit a suspect access to legal representation [italic]during interrogation[/italic] only in cases where the suspect is charged with a Tier III crime or greater;

  [bold]S3.05.[/bold] The Warden may not hand out any weapons or armor from the Armory, except for extra disablers. Hardsuits may be issued if emergency E.V.A action is required. Exception is made if there is an immediate threat that requires attention, such as Nuclear Operatives;

  [bold]S3.06.[/bold] The Warden is permitted to carry a fully kitted security belt and a standard issue pistol. While permitted to carry their unique energy shotgun, they are discouraged from doing so for safety concerns, and should keep it on disable;

  [bold]S3.07.[/bold] The Warden may not place the portable flashers within the Brig;

  [bold]S3.08.[/bold] The Warden may not place the deployable barriers within the Brig;

  [bold]S3.09.[/bold] The Warden must read to every prisoner the crimes they are sentenced to;

  [bold]S3.10.[/bold] The Warden is not permitted to leave prisoners cuffed to their beds. An exception is made if the prisoners acts overtly hostile or attempts to breach the cell in order to escape;

  [bold]S3.11.[/bold] The Warden must follow the same guidelines as Security Officers for attire, with the exception that their own assigned attire is also acceptable for any of the attire mentioned for Security Officers;

  [bold]S3.12.[/bold] The Warden is encouraged to follow the Security Rules of Conduct to set a proper example for cadets, as well as establish trust with the public.

  ## Code Blue

  [bold]S3.01B.[/bold] Guidelines 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 9, 11 and 12 are carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

  [bold]S3.02B.[/bold] The Warden is permitted to hand out all equipment from the Armory. Guns are only to be handed out with Head of Security or Captain's approval, as they present a lethal risk, or if there is an immediate threat, such as Nuclear Operatives;

  [bold]S3.03B.[/bold] The Warden is permitted to place the portable flashers inside the Brig;

  [bold]S3.04B.[/bold] The Warden is permitted to place the deployable barriers inside the Brig.

  ## Code Red

  [bold]S3.01R.[/bold] Guidelines 2, 4, 6, 9, 11 and 12 are carried over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

  [bold]S3.02R.[/bold] Guidelines 3 and 4 are carried over from Code Blue. In addition, the Warden may also carry any weapon from the Armory, but never more than one at a time;

  [bold]S3.03R.[/bold] The Warden is not required to permit a trial during states of emergency. However, the Warden is still required to permit the suspect access to confidential meetings with their chosen legal representative at any time during their sentence, and the suspect's brig time should not be advanced during these confidential meetings.

  [bold]S3.04R.[/bold] The Warden is permitted to distribute any weapon or piece of equipment in the Armory. This includes whatever Research has provided;

  [bold]S3.05R.[/bold] The Warden is permitted to carry out arrests freely.

  # Detective

  ## Code Green

  [bold]S4.01.[/bold] The Detective is permitted to assist Security Officers with all Patrol Duties. This includes stops, searches, and arrests as per the current Alert Code. They should, however, prioritize investigations and the collection of forensic evidence;

  [bold]S4.02.[/bold] The Detective is to follow all Standard Operating Procedures as outlined by the Security Officer SoP in regard to stops, searches and arrests as per the current Alert Code;

  [bold]S4.03.[/bold] The Detective may carry their revolver and spare ammunition;

  [bold]S4.04.[/bold] The Detective may carry a fully kitted out security belt;

  [bold]S4.05.[/bold] The Detective is permitted to wear non-Security clothing with permission from the Head of Security for the purpose of undercover investigations. They are, however, expected to carry their Security ID on their person at all times;

  [bold]S4.06.[/bold] When not undercover, the Detective must follow the same guidelines as Security Officers for attire, with the exception that their own assigned attire is also acceptable for any of the attire mentioned for Security Officers.

  ## Code Blue

  [bold]S4.01B.[/bold] All Guidelines carry over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

  [bold]S4.02B.[/bold] The Detective may pull aside any suspect for an interrogation during the course of their time in Processing. If the suspect requests legal representation during interrogation, the Detective is required to permit it only if the suspect is charged with a Tier III crime or greater. No detainee is to be held for longer than ten (10) minutes in Processing if no evidence against them is readily available.

  [bold]S4.03B.[/bold] Torture as a means to gather evidence is allowed.

  ## Code Red

  [bold]S4.01R.[/bold] Guidelines 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5 carry over from [color=green]Code Green[/color];

  [bold]S4.02R.[/bold] Guidelines 2 and 3 carry over from [color=cyan]Code Blue[/color];

  [bold]S4.03R.[/bold] The Detective is permitted to carry around any weapons or equipment available in the Armory, at the Warden's discretion, but never more than one at a time. Exception is made for severe emergencies, such as Nuclear Operatives;
</Document>
