<Document>
# Genetics

The Genetics system allows medical personnel and scientists to analyze, modify, and apply genetic mutations to living beings. It is a powerful but risky tool that can grant extraordinary abilities-or cause severe harm through genetic instability and cellular damage.

## Core Equipment

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MedicalScanner" Caption="medical scanner" Rotation="0"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerDnaScanner" Caption="geneticists console" Rotation="0"/>
</Box>

### DNA Scanner & Console
The medical scanner is the pod-like machine that holds the patient (drag & drop or use the "eject occupant" verb).
The geneticists console (placed nearby) provides the full interface and must be powered and linked to the scanner.

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HandheldGeneticAnalyzer" Caption="handheld genetic analyzer" Rotation="0"/>
</Box>

### Handheld Genetic Analyzer
A portable device that quickly scans a target's mutations and genetic instability, allowing you to print them out for later viewing.
Requires a power cell.

## The Basics

Place a living subject into the DNA scanner.

Sit at the DNA scanner console and open the UI.

Use the sequencer to reveal the correct DNA sequence for each mutation.

Save useful mutations to the console's storage.

Print DNA activators or DNA mutators to apply mutations to others.

Use the handheld genetic analyzer for quick checks without needing the scanner.

## Using the DNA Scanner Console

The console UI includes several sections:

Subject Info - Name, total damage, genetic instability, and health status.

Mutation List - Shows all mutations in the patient's DNA.

Revealed Sequence - Current known bases (X = unknown).

Sequencer - Click bases to change them (each click deals 0.2 cellular damage). When the revealed sequence matches the original, the mutation becomes active.

Saved Mutations - Store discovered mutations here for printing.

Print Activator / Print Mutator - Creates a single-use injector from a saved mutation.

Scramble DNA - Randomly resets the patient's DNA (30-second cooldown, causes 25 cellular damage).

## DNA Injectors

<Box>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DNAInjectorGenericActivator" Caption="DNA activator" Rotation="0"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DNAInjectorGenericMutator" Caption="DNA mutator" Rotation="0"/>
<GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DNAInjectorEmpty" Caption="empty DNA injector" Rotation="0"/>
</Box>

- Activators - Activate a mutation that is already present.
- Mutators - Add and activate a new mutation (if the target can accept it).
- Both are single-use and leave an empty injector behind.

## Mutations & Genetic Instability

Mutations are stored in blocks with a fixed sequence of bases (A, C, G, T).
Revealing the correct sequence in the console activates the mutation.

Each added mutation increases Genetic Instability by its instability value.

Instability thresholds:
  - >100 - Risk of a dangerous random mutation after 60-90 seconds.
  - >150 - Constant cellular damage over time.

Scramble DNA resets everything (except scramble-resistant mutations) but is very deals heavy genetic damage.

## Tips & Safety

- Sequencing and scrambling both cause cellular damage-monitor the patient's health.
- Mutadone can remove unwanted mutations (some are resistant).
- Radiation damage can trigger random mutations.
- Some mutations are species-specific or incapable of natural generation.

With careful use, Genetics can transform ordinary crew into superhumans-or create horrifying abominations. Use responsibly!
</Document>
