<Document>
  # Standard Operating Procedure

  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"The station is currently under threat of imminent destruction. Crewmembers are advised to listen to heads of staff for more information."[/italic][/color]
  </Box>

  Consider SOP your new space bible, feature complete with ways to lethal people legally.

  # What is Standard Operating Procedure? (SOP)

  Standard Operating Procedure, from hereon out known as SOP, is how NanoTrasen is expected to run its facilities. This ensures proper treatment of prisoners, how to safely deal with certain situations, and how to identify positive threats on the station.
  Deviating from SOP is a big and conscious decision, and any actions you may take while deviating from SOP may be grounds for discipline and/or termination of your contract.

  [bold]Job SOP should not be a considered a checklist of conditions to fire someone over, and should not be rigidly followed to the letter in detriment of circumstances and context. As always, SOP can be malleable if the situation so requires, and the decision to punish a crewmember for breaching it ultimately falls onto the relevant Head of Staff, for Department Members, or Captain, for the Head of Staff.[/bold]

  # Isn't SOP just guidelines?

  Yes they are, but following them ensures to establish proper trust with the public. Otherwise, you may be regarded as "Shitsec", or even worse, "Shitsci", so it's always wise to consult the appropriate SOP document for your department. If you need to break SOP, you better have a good reason to justify its breakage afterward.

  # Great, now where can I find the SOP for my department?

  You can find all department SOP documents here:

  - [textlink="Alert Levels and You" link="AlertLevelsSOP"]
  - [textlink="Command SOP" link="CommandSOP"]
  - [textlink="Security SOP" link="SecuritySOP"]
  - [textlink="Legal SOP" link="LegalSOP"]
  - [textlink="Medical SOP" link="MedicalSOP"]
  - [textlink="Service SOP" link="ServiceSOP"]
  - [textlink="Engineering SOP" link="EngineeringSOP"]
  - [textlink="Cargo SOP" link="CargoSOP"]

</Document>
