<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 kbarkevich <24629810+kbarkevich@users.noreply.github.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Lawyer

  [bold]1.[/bold] Lawyers are only to provide legal representation during interrogation to personnel facing charges of Tier III or greater. Lawyers are only permitted to provide legal representation in a court of law to personnel facing a Tier IV sentence or greater. They should, however, ensure that all timed sentences are applied correctly, and alert Security if it is not. In addition, Lawyers are permitted to provide legal advice to prisoners, as well as investigating whether or not arrests were done properly;

  [bold]2.[/bold] Lawyers must request permission from any potential client before serving as their legal representative, as said client may choose to either represent themselves, or request someone else;

  [bold]3.[/bold] Lawyers are not to deliberately halt or slow down prisoner processing or ongoing investigations. If Security is acting in a demonstrably incompetent manner, Lawyers should contact the Head of Security or the Captain. If more information about the crime in question is needed, Lawyers should wait until the person in question is brigged;

  [bold]4.[/bold] Lawyers are permitted to confidentially speak with their clients prior to any interrogation. Time spent conferring with a Lawyer may not be counted as time served during a timed sentence. If a client wishes to speak confidentially with their Lawyer during a timed sentence, the time remaining on their sentence must be frozen and may only resumed once the client has re-entered their cell. Lawyers may not divulge the contents of these confidential meetings without the explicit permission of their clients, except in cases where there are reasons to believe that their silence may endanger the lives and safety of other station personnel. If a Lawyer fails to divulge information that was found to later directly lead to the injury or death of personnel, the Lawyer should be charged as an accessory to the resulting crimes;

  # Trials

  [bold]1.[/bold] Only Tier IV (if the ranking Judge on the station consents) crimes and Tier V (if the defendant and their legal representative demand it) crimes should be brought to trial;

  [bold]2.[/bold] Expedient application of Space Law is preferred over a trial process, trials should be reserved for when the defendant and their legal representative can reasonably claim that the justification for a sentence is objectionable and the station is not currently in a state of emergency;

  [bold]3.[/bold] Only the Magistrate, Captain, or Nanotrasen Representative may assume the role of Judge and convene a trial. The Magistrate can overrule the Captain and the Nanotrasen Representative, while the Captain may only overrule the Nanotrasen Representative;

  [bold]4.[/bold] Security may, but is not required to act as legal representation or attend a trial, even as witnesses;

  [bold]5.[/bold] When provided by defendants, legal representation must be permitted in the trial to speak on their behalf. Though Lawyers may be the most suited for the role, there are no restrictions on who may represent a defendant;

  [bold]6.[/bold] Before beginning a trial, the Judge should obtain a statement or "affidivat" with a full recount of the defendant's and any relevant witnesses' testimony of the events from their perspective;

  [bold]7.[/bold] The Judge must ensure that decorum is kept during a trial and that the proceedings are timely;

  ## Official Courtroom Proceedings

  Judges must strictly enforce the following procedure during a trial. The Judge should be mindful of the time and set time limits for each part of the proceeds. The gavel may be struck when a party goes beyond their time limit;

  [bold]1.[/bold] The Prosecution presents its opening statement;

  [bold]2.[/bold] The Defense presents its opening statement;

  [bold]3.[/bold] The Defendant is questioned first by the defense and then cross-examined by the Prosecution;

  [bold]4.[/bold] Any relevant witnesses are questioned. The party that introduced the witness gets to examine them first, after which the other side is given a chance to cross-examine the witness;

  [bold]5.[/bold] The Prosecution presents its closing statement;

  [bold]6.[/bold] The Defense presents its closing statement;

  [bold]7.[/bold] The Judge issues a verdict, which should be considered the final sentence in regards to the defendant. Only Central Command may override this verdict;

  ## Contempt of Court

  It is required that all parties inside the courtroom, and during the court proceedings, must act with dignity and respect. This includes, but is not limited to, recognizing the authority of the Judge, maintaining an appropriate level of verbal control, and generally acting in a civilized manner. Should a person inside the courtroom act in such a way as to disturb/disrupt court proceedings, the Judge may hold them in Contempt of Court and have them forcefully removed from the courtroom. The decision on whether or not a person is in Contempt of Court rests with the presiding Judge.
</Document>
