<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tay <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->
<Document>
# Captain SOP

[bold]1.[/bold] The Captain is [bold]not[/bold] permitted to perform regular Security Duty. However, they may still assist [color=#cb0000]Security[/color] if they are understaffed, or if they see a crime being committed.

[bold]2.[/bold] The Captain is [bold]not[/bold] permitted to take items from the Armory under normal circumstances, unless authorized by the [color=#cb0000]Head of Security[/color]. In addition, the Captain may not requisition weaponry for themselves from [color=#b18644]Cargo[/color] and/or [color=#c96dbf]Science[/color], unless there's an [bold]immediate[/bold] threat to station and/or crew;

[bold]3.[/bold] If a Department lacks a [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color], the Captain should make reasonable efforts to appoint an [color=#1b67a5]Acting Head of Staff[/color], if there are available personnel to fill the position. The [color=#1b67a5]Acting Head of Staff[/color] [bold]must[/bold] be a member of the Department vetted prior to shift start by [color=#009100]Central Command[/color], not a promoted member from another department;

[bold]4.[/bold] The Captain is [bold]not[/bold] to leave the Station unless given specific permission by [color=#009100]Central Command[/color], or it happens to be the end of the shift. To do so is to be considered abandoning their posts and is grounds for termination;

[bold]5.[/bold] The Captain must keep the Nuclear Authentication Disk on their person at all times or failing that, in the possession of the [color=#cb0000]Head of Security[/color];

[bold]6.[/bold] The Captain is to attempt to resolve every issue that arises in [color=#1b67a5]Command[/color] locally before contacting [color=#009100]Central Command[/color];

[bold]7.[/bold] The Captain, despite being in charge of the Station, is not separate from [color=#134975]Nanotrasen[/color]. Any attempts to disregard general company policy are to be considered an instant condition for contract termination;

[bold]8.[/bold] The Captain may not fire any [color=#1b67a5]Head of Staff[/color] without reasonable justification (ie, incompetency, criminal activity, or otherwise any action that endangers/compromises the station and/or crew). The Captain may not fire any [color=#009100]Central Command Staff[/color] ([color=#009100]Nanotrasen Representative[/color], etc) without permission from [color=#009100]Central Command[/color]. If such crewmembers are blatantly acting against the well-being and safety of the crew and station, the Captain has the authority to confine them to their quarters pending a response from [color=#009100]Central Command[/color].

[bold]9.[/bold] The Captain must follow the SOP of any role who's duties they explicitly perform or whos authority they explicitly invoke while performing said duties or invoking said authority.

## Captain OOC Rules

[bold]1.[/bold] You should not be acting in the capacity of a dictator and micromanaging every aspect of the station. When you act as the HoP for example to give accesses, you need to follow their SOP and get approval from the head of staff of that department.
</Document>
