<Document>
  # Command Training Manual

  Welcome to your new job, command member.

  We at Nanotrasen praise your dedication to safety and willingness to do anything for the wellbeing of the corporation.
  Below, you will find training material regarding the confidential information you were informed of prior.

  The following material is available for your reference, training, and use.
  The information is designed to assist Command members in their professional development.
  Please use the material to expand your understanding, enhance your professional knowledge, and to further your career.

  Please also remember that all of this material is [bold]confidential,[/bold] as per the NDA you signed on employment.
  Failure to comply with the terms of your employment will be met with swift legal action.

  ## Section I. Confidentiality

  All the information in this document is for your eyes only. You, and your fellow command members, are [bold]not[/bold] to share this information without sufficient reason.

  Carelessly leaking this confidential information will be met with swift action from Central Command; whether that be through one of its representatives or through the organization itself.
  You, as one of the leaders of the station, are to lead the crew through any potential dangers. Needlessly sowing fear within the crew is explicitly against this goal, and it is also against Nanotrasen's will.
  Nanotrasen and its associated ships and stations are safe. You, as a primary representative of corporate's will, must make sure this fact stays true.

  However, the crew may still experience situations that require you to divulge otherwise confidential information.
  We at Nanotrasen trust you to divulge this information at your discretion, and we remind any command members that any unnecessary confidentiality breaks will not be treated kindly.
  After any such confidentiality breaks, you are to report what information was divulged, when, to who, and why. These reports may be made to your Nanotrasen Representative or Central Command itself.
  The Nanotrasen Representative will inform command members if the confidentiality break was done in good faith, and they will report back as necessary.

  ## Section II. Threats

  Below you will find a list of threats and recommended action to dealing with them.

  [color=red]This is recommended action, not explicit operating procedure.[/color]
  We at Nanotrasen understand that shifts may deviate from the expected results, so no action will be taken against you or your fellow crew mates for mistakes.

  - [bold]Petty thieves[/bold]

  Petty thievery is common, especially the further out in space that you may be stationed. Deal with any thieves under space law.
  These thieves may have contraband that your security team is not made aware of. The Head of Security should consider only divulging information about said contraband
  to the Detective, as to not cause any undue fear.

  - [bold]Undercover Syndicate Agents[/bold]

  Nanotrasen property and people are a consistent target for the Syndicate, however, the crew should not have to worry about any such issues. Deal with said agents under space law and with discretion.
  Command members should only consider divulging information about the Syndicate if there is a noticeable and constant presence on the station, and even then, they should consider only informing the security team.

  - [bold]Revolutionaries[/bold]

  Nanotrasen crew members may become upset with the working conditions. Consider dealing with this as peacefully as possible, such as offering free pizza parties.
  However, if the crew remains dissatisfied with the working conditions, it is possible that their loyalty to Nanotrasen has been tampered with.
  Instruct the security team to mindshield as many crew mates as possible, and arrest and mindshield any crew members spearheading the cause.
  In the event of a particularly disruptive head revolutionary, execution is also an option, but not recommended.

  - [bold]Nuclear Agents[/bold]

  Some Syndicate agents are specifically on station in order to detonate the emergency nuclear device. This is a highly dangerous emergency situation, and security should be armed to deal with the threat as soon as possible.
  Crew members should be instructed to shelter in place, as they are civilians with no security training or experience. In the event of a weak or nonexistent security force, command may enlist and arm crew mates as necessary.

  - [bold]Blob Xenofauna[/bold]

  Central Command's sensors can detect any dangerous xenofauna above a certain size, and will send an automatic announcement. Neutralize the threat as soon as possible, under any circumstance.

  - [bold]Changelings[/bold]

  Some crew mates may not be crew mates at all; a hostile predatory life form, colloquially known as changelings, may have taken a similar form as them.
  These creatures are to be dealt with discreetly and quickly, as they require the death of crew in order to survive.
  Since these life forms have been known as extinct to the public, it is recommended to lie to the crew in order to preserve the hard work of Nanotrasen's marketing team.

  - [bold]Dragons and Carp[/bold]

  Dragons are incredibly territorial and hostile xenofauna, and they should be dealt with as quickly as possible.
  There is no need to keep such the existence of such xenofauna a secret to the crew, however, Nanotrasen encourages the security team to try and keep crew from panicking.

  - [bold]Ninjas[/bold]

  Some people may attempt to infiltrate the station with the goal of stealing Nanotrasen secrets and research. These are likely ninjas, and they should be dealt with as soon as possible.
  Nanotrasen recommends trying to discreetly deal with them as soon as possible to prevent any sort of espionage, regardless of the intention.

  - [bold]Revenants[/bold]

  Some former crew mates may find it hard to move on after an untimely death caused by their own negligence.
  Nanotrasen recommends enlisting the Chaplain as an exorcist, without letting the living crew know about any prior deaths on the station.

  - [bold]Heretics[/bold]

  Some individual crewmates may find ways to use more magical powers. These powers are heretical and not sanctioned by Nanotrasen. You should try to neutralize their powers while still keeping their work contract intact.
  The Head of Security should consider only divulging information regarding the specific case, such as heretics being able to teleport with a magical focus.

  - [bold]Cults[/bold]

  In contrast, cults are highly dangerous, organized groups of magical power.
  The Head of Security may consider telling all the security force and the chaplain about a cult presence.
  The chaplain, in particular, should be protected and made aware of any events.

  - [bold]Zombies[/bold]

  In the event of a zombie infection, the Chief Medical Officer and their associated medical team should be made the highest priority on the station.
  Due to the nature of zombie infections, there is no need to withhold any information about them. The station alert level should be set to Violet and go into an emergency state.
</Document>
