<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 DevilishMilk <bluscout78@yahoo.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2024 Tadeo <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Tay <td12233a@gmail.com>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  Here is a list of all the SOP documents for command.

  # Captain SOP

  [bold]1.[/bold] The Captain is not permitted to perform regular Security Duty. However, they may still assist Security if they are understaffed, or if they see a crime being committed. However, the Captain is not permitted to take items from the Armory under normal circumstances, unless authorized by the Head of Security. In addition, the Captain may not requisition weaponry for themselves from Cargo and/or Science, unless there's an immediate threat to station and/or crew;

  [bold]2.[/bold] If a Department lacks a Head of Staff, the Captain should make reasonable efforts to appoint an Acting Head of Staff, if there are available personnel to fill the position;

  [bold]3.[/bold] The Captain is to ensure that Space Law is being correctly applied. This should be done in cooperation with the Head of Security;

  [bold]4.[/bold] The Captain is not to leave the Station unless given specific permission by Central Command, or it happens to be the end of the shift. To do so is to be considered abandoning their posts and is grounds for termination;

  [bold]5.[/bold] The Captain must keep the Nuclear Authentication Disk on their person at all times or failing that, in the possession of the Head of Security or Blueshield;

  [bold]6.[/bold] The Captain is to attempt to resolve every issue that arises in Command locally before contacting Central Command;

  [bold]7.[/bold] The Captain, despite being in charge of the Station, is not separate from NanoTrasen. Any attempts to disregard general company policy are to be considered an instant condition for contract termination;

  [bold]8.[/bold] The Captain may only promote personnel to an Acting Head of Staff position if there is no assigned Head of Staff associated with the Department. The Acting Head of Staff must be a member of the Department they are to lead. See below for more information on Chain of Command;

  [bold]9.[/bold] The Captain may not fire any Head of Staff without reasonable justification (ie, incompetency, criminal activity, or otherwise any action that endangers/compromises the station and/or crew). The Captain may not fire any Central Command VIPs (ie, Blueshield, NanoTrasen Representative) without permission from Central Command, unless they are blatantly acting against the well-being and safety of the crew and station. The Captain must also follow HoP SOP point 5.

  # Head of Personnel SOP

  [bold]1.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may not transfer any personnel to another Department without authorization from the relevant Head of Staff. If no Head of Staff is available, the Head of Personnel may make a judgment call. This does not apply to Security, which always requires authorization from the Head of Security, or Genetics, which requires both Chief Medical Officer and Research Director approval. If there is no Head of Security active, no transfers are allowed to Security without authorization from the Captain;

  [bold]2.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may not give any personnel increased access without authorization from the relevant Head of Staff. This includes the Head of Personnel. In addition, the Head of Personnel may only give Captain-Level access to someone if they are the Acting Captain. This access is to be removed when a proper Captain arrives at the station;

  [bold]3.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may not increase any Job Openings unless the relevant Head of Staff approves;

  [bold]4.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may not fire any personnel without authorization from the relevant Head of Staff, unless other conditions apply (see Space Law and General Standard Operating Procedure);

  [bold]5.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may not promote anyone to the job of NanoTrasen Representative or Blueshield;

  [bold]6.[/bold] The Head of Personnel is free to utilize paperwork at their discretion. However, during major station emergencies, expediency should take precedence over bureaucracy;

  [bold]7.[/bold] The Head of Personnel may not leave their office unmanned if there are personnel waiting in line. Failure to respond to personnel with a legitimate request within ten (10) minutes, either via radio or in person is to be considered a breach of Standard Operating Procedure;

  [bold]8.[/bold] The Head of Personnel is not permitted to perform Security duty. The Head of Personnel is permitted to carry a Disabler for self-defense only.

  # NanoTrasen Representative SOP

  [bold]1.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative is to ensure that every Department is following Standard Operating Procedure, up to and including the respective Head of Staff. If a Head of Staff is not available for a Department, the NanoTrasen Representative must ensure that the Captain appoints an Acting Head of Staff for said Department;

  [bold]2.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative must attempt to resolve any breach of Standard Operating Procedure locally before contacting Central Command. This is an imperative: Standard Operating Procedure should always be followed unless there is a very good reason not to;

  [bold]3.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative must, together with the Head of Security, ensure that Space Law is being followed and correctly applied;

  [bold]4.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative may not threaten the use of a fax in order to gain leverage over any personnel, up to and including Command. In addition, they may not threaten to fire or have Central Command fire anyone, unless they actually possess a demotion note;

  [bold]5.[/bold] The NanoTrasen Representative is permitted to carry their flash and a blade-cane, or a stun baton if the blade-cane is lost.

  # Blueshield Officer SOP

  [bold]1.[/bold] The Blueshield may not conduct arrests under the same conditions as Security. However, they may apprehend any personnel that trespass on a Head of Staff Office or Command Area, any personnel that steal from those locations, or any personnel that steal from and/or injure any Head of Staff or Central Command VIP. However, all apprehended personnel are to be processed by Security personnel;

  [bold]2.[/bold] The Blueshield is to put the lives of Command over those of any other personnel, the Blueshield included. Their continued well-being is the Blueshield's top priority. This includes applying basic first aid and making sure they are revived if killed;

  [bold]3.[/bold] The Blueshield is to protect the lives of Command personnel, not follow their orders to a fault. The Blueshield is not to interfere with legal demotions or arrests. To do so is to place themselves under the Special Modifier Aiding and Abetting;

  [bold]4.[/bold] The Blueshield is not to apply Lethal Force unless there is a clear and present danger to their life, or to the life of a member of Command and the assailant cannot be non-lethally detained.

  # Magistrate SOP

  [bold]1.[/bold] The Magistrate is to ensure that Space Law is applied correctly. If it is not, they are to make it so;
  
  [bold]2.[/bold] The Magistrate has the final say on whether Trials take place, and should ensure they should only occur for Capital Sentences. Similarly, Magistrates are to ensure that Trials do not happen for Defendants that are self-evidently guilty;
  
  [bold]3.[/bold] The Magistrate may overrule anyone in all matters concerning Space Law. This does not extend to Emergency Response Teams, Central Command Officials or direct Central Command communications;
  
  [bold]4.[/bold] The Magistrate is permitted to carry their flash;
  
  [bold]5.[/bold] The Magistrate is not above Space Law. Similarly, the Magistrate cannot overrule Security on a sentence imposed against themselves;
  
  [bold]6.[/bold] In the absence of Internal Affairs Agents or a NanoTrasen Representative, the Magistrate may elect to handle matters of Standard Operating Procedure. Otherwise, the Magistrate is only to ensure that the NanoTrasen Representative under their command are handling such matters;

  [bold]7.[/bold] The Magistrate may not impede the expedient functioning of Security for the sake of micromanaging every aspect it. The Magistrate should only concern themselves with crimes that either have fuzzy evidence, or require careful deliberation of circumstances;

  [bold]8.[/bold] The Magistrate is to contact Central Command immediately if their decisions are being ignored, provided said decision actually match up with Space Law and Standard Operating Procedure.
  
  # If you need to deviate,

  [bold]Document document document![/bold]
  After action reports, calling CentCom on the fabled red phone, or even praying will be heard by CentCom and your actions may be excused if they were determined to be in the best interest for NanoTrasen.

  # I don't see my job listed here!

  It may be because this is a living document, and SOP is not yet finalized. The following SOP documents are completed for other Head's of Staff;

  -[textlink="Head of Security SOP" link="SecuritySOP"]

  Glory to NanoTrasen!
</Document>
