<!--
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 Goomson <GoomsonCode@proton.me>
SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2025 taydeo <td12233a@gmail.com>

SPDX-License-Identifier: MIT
-->

<Document>
  # Reactions
  Here are some chemicals that, when utilized properly, have unique effects!


  #Creation reactions

  When mixing some chemicals, items can be created!

  Some of the easiest recipes for an aspiring chemist to understand are the simple recipes that help with making items.


  ##Soap
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Soap" Caption="Soap"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SoapHomemade" Caption="Homemade Soap"/>
  </Box>
  Soap can be made with the following reagents:

  -15u Fat
  -10u Table Salt
  -10u Water (or) 10u Blood
  
  You can also make a homemade variant by swapping out water with blood!

  ##Meat
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoodMeat" Caption="Meat"/>
  </Box>
  You can make synthetic meat with:
  -25u Fat
  -5u Nutriment
  -10u Blood
  -10u Carbon

  ##Plastic
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SheetPlastic" Caption="Plastic"/>
  </Box>
  You can make plastic by heating the following reagents to 374K:

  -5u Oil
  -3u Ash
  -2u Sulfuric Acid

  ##Crystals

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShardCrystalGreen" Caption="Green Crystal"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShardCrystalCyan" Caption="Cyan Crystal"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShardCrystalPink" Caption="Pink Crystal"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShardCrystalRed" Caption="Red Crystal"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ShardCrystalOrange" Caption="Orange Crystal"/>
  </Box>
  You can create synthetic crystals for decoration by mixing and heating to 374k:

  -15u Sugar
  -15u Water
  -5u Ethanol

  ##Gunpowder
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MaterialGunpowder" Caption="Gunpowder"/>
  </Box>
  You can create gunpowder, a component used in improvised explosives, by mixing:
  -6u Potassium
  -2u Sulfur
  -2u Charcoal

  ##Solidification
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="IngotGold1" Caption="Gold"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="IngotSilver1" Caption="Silver"/>
  </Box>
  You can solidify reagents such as silver and gold into bars by using:
  -10u Metal (silver or gold)
  -5u Frost Oil


  # Gas reactions

  When mixing some chemicals, gas can be created!

  This can be beneficial or [color=red]HIGHLY DANGEROUS[/color] depending on the context in which it is used!

  ## Plasma Gas
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="PlasmaCanister" Caption="Plasma Gas"/>
  </Box>
  One of the most basic and dangerous gas reactions is the gaseous plasma that is made while mixing Phlogiston.

  The recipe to make this (and release the gas) is:

  -1 part Plasma
  -1 part Phosphorus
  -1 part Sulfuric Acid

  ## Frezon
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FrezonCanister" Caption="Frezon Gas"/>
  </Box>
  Another effect can be used to make Frezon gas, which is very damaging to the stations atmosphere. Please wear your winter coats!

  The reaction to create Frezon gas is:

  -1 part Fresium
  -1 part Water

  # Foam reactions

  There are two types of [color=cyan]foam[/color] reactions.

  ##Reagent Foam

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Beaker" Caption="Fluorosurfactant"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Beaker" Caption="Water"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Beaker" Caption="(Optional) reagent(s)"/>
  </Box>

  [color=cyan]Reagent[/color] foam applies whatever chemical is in the solution to those within it's radius- this is different from [color=cyan]smoke[/color] because it can apply reagents topically as well.

  Reagent foam leaves residue on the floor when utilized with drinks or other liquids, so be sure to take this into account while making mixes!

  More Fluorosurfactant and water mean more spread- but be aware this doesn't increase the potency of the foam, which depends on how much of the reagent you put in the solution.
  Enjoy mixing and creating your own foam!

  To make reagent foam you mix:

  -1 part Fluorosurfactant
  -1 part Water
  -(Optional) Any amount of Reagent


  ## Metal Foam
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MetalFoamGrenade" Caption="Metal Foam"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoamedIronMetal" Caption="Foamed Iron"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FoamedAluminiumMetal" Caption="Foamed Aluminum"/>
  </Box>
  [color=cyan]Metal[/color] foam creates fairly sturdy walls made of solidified foam metal. This also can be utilized for a variety of purposes, such as sealing hallways, hull breaches, and more!
  To make metal foam you mix:

  -3 parts metal (Iron, Aluminum)
  -1 part Foaming Agent
  -1 part Fluorosulfuric acid

  Be aware that the fluorosulfuric acid will hurt anyone near it before it solidifies!
  Increasing the reactants will increase the size of the foam area.


  # Smoke reactions
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SmokeGrenade" Caption="Smoke Grenade"/>
  </Box>
  When mixing some chemicals, smoke can coat the area!

  This causes any [color=cyan]reagents[/color] within the mix to be ingested by anyone who breathes it in, which can result in many fun (or deadly!) effects!

  The basic recipe to mix smoke is:
  -1 part Phosphorous
  -1 part Potassium
  -1 part Sugar
  -(Optional) Any amount of reagent

  More of the reagents mean a larger area of effect, and adding more reagents will result in larger quantities of whatever is in solution being inhaled by those without internals on.

  # Explosive reactions

  When mixing some chemicals, explosions can be caused!

  ##Potassium and Water
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Beaker" Caption="Potassium"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Beaker" Caption="Water"/>
  </Box>
  The most basic of explosions is mixing:

  -1 Part Potassium
  -1 Part Water

  This will instantly cause a small but easily scalable explosion, which releases heat and can shatter windows! This can be used for chaining effects together with larger explosive payloads, such as CLF3!


  ##CLF3
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Beaker" Caption="Chlorine"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Beaker" Caption="Fluorine"/>
  </Box>

  Some more advanced explosions can be formed by mixing and then heating to 370K:
  -1 part Chlorine
  -3 parts Fluorine

  Be aware that this WILL cause an explosion as soon as the CLF3 is hot enough to be made! This will likely result in it's loss unless precautions are taken.


  ##EMPs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EmpGrenade" Caption="Emp"/>
  </Box>
  To make a homemade EMP, which will immediately knock out any electronics in the area; you use:

  -1 part Aluminum
  -1 part Iron
  -1 part Uranium

  As with other area of effect tools, the size and will increase the more reagents you use.

  ##Flashbangs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="GrenadeFlashBang" Caption="Flashbang"/>
  </Box>
  To make a homemade flashbang, capable of disorienting and confusing people within it's radius, you use:

  -1 part Aluminum
  -1 part Potassium
  -1 part Sulfur

  Size and radius increase with the reagent amounts.



</Document>
